<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>marshall charlotte death cert order form</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/lovejoy/marshall_charlotte_death_cert_order_form/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/lovejoy/marshall_charlotte_death_cert_order_form/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>_NEW YORK STATE«EPARTMENTOF HEALTH
<lb/>'vital Records Section, Genealogy Unit
<lb/>Corning Tower Building, Empire State Plaza
<lb/>Albany„New York 12237-0023
<lb/>General information and Application
<lb/>for Genealogical Services
<lb/>VITAL RECORDS COPIES CANNOT BE PROVIDED FOR COMMERCIAL PURPOSES.
<lb/>1. FEE - $11.00 includes search and uncertified copy or notification of no record.
<lb/>2. Origirtal records of births and marriages for the entire state begin with 1881, deaths begin with 1880, EXCEPT for records
<lb/>filed in Albany, Buffalo and Yonkers prior to 1914. Applications for these cities should be made directly to the local office.
<lb/>3. The New York State Department of Health does not have New York City records except for births occurring in Queens and
<lb/>Richmond counties for the years 1881 through 1897.
<lb/>4. Please read the Administrative Rule Summary on the reverse side of this sheet which specifies years available for genealogical
<lb/>research.
<lb/>To insure a complete search, provide as much Information as possible. Please complete for
<lb/>type of record requested, birth, death OR marriage.
<lb/>m
<lb/>Name at Birth.
<lb/>Date of Birth
<lb/>Place of Birth
<lb/>Father's Name
<lb/>Mother's Maiden Name
<lb/>SZ
<lb/>k.
<lb/>CQ
<lb/>Name at Birth.
<lb/>Date of Birth
<lb/>Place of Birth
<lb/>Father's Name
<lb/>Mother's Maiden Name
<lb/>0)
<lb/>(0
<lb/>(d
<lb/>Name of Bride _
<lb/>Name of Groom
<lb/>Date of Marriage
<lb/>Piace of Marriage
<lb/>and/or License
<lb/>0)ui(0(0
<lb/>Name of Bride _
<lb/>Name of Groom
<lb/>Date of Marriage _
<lb/>Place of Marriage
<lb/>and/or License
<lb/>f
<lb/>Name at Death CLittrUiug
<lb/>Death Age at Death ^ i&gt;
<lb/>Name at Death 11 VA' . Ca
<lb/>O
<lb/>Place of Death
<lb/>Q
<lb/>Date of Death 1, lyif Age at Death
<lb/>Place of Death ..jUu-m'SWibI'I't $ g I j
<lb/>Names of Parents
<lb/>Name of Spouse A V't a L
<lb/>Names of Parents
<lb/>Name of Spouse
<lb/>ri
<lb/>l-n
<lb/>tr
<lb/>For what purpose is information required?
<lb/>What is your relationship to person whose record is requested? c-c?-'&gt;o u,
<lb/>In what capacity are you acting? sc-f
<lb/>SIGNATURE OF APPLICANT
<lb/>ADDRESS i
<lb/>DATE &lt; f
<lb/>Send record to: (please print)
<lb/>Name CHfis MosLer
<lb/>If requesting birth and marriage records, please sign the following
<lb/>statement:
<lb/>To the best of my knowledge, the person(s) named in the
<lb/>applicatioi^re d^eased.Address Rtd^elev A^e
<lb/>Gitv State Zip Code SIGNATUI^OFAPPLICANT
<lb/>DOH-1562 (10/91) p. 1 of 2
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/>
<lb/>Health Commissioner's
<lb/>Administrative Rules and Regulations
<lb/>Summary
<lb/>Genealogical Research
<lb/>Uncertified copies or abstracts from records of birth, death, and marriage may be provided for
<lb/>genealogical research purposes subject to the restrictions specified in this summary. All requests
<lb/>must be submitted in writing and include payment of the applicable statutory fee. The applicant shall
<lb/>be required to pay the specified fee for the time spent for the search and uncertified copy or
<lb/>notification of no record.
<lb/>2. Who Is authorized to do the searching?
<lb/>Record searches shall be conducted only by the following persons in the files maintained by their
<lb/>respective agencies:
<lb/>a. authorized employees of the State Department of Health;
<lb/>b. a local registrar, deputy registrar, or an authorized employee of the registrar;
<lb/>c. a town or city clerk, deputy clerk, or an authorized employee of the town or city clerk.
<lb/>3. What records are available?
<lb/>a.b.c.d.e.f.
<lb/>No information shall be released from a record of birth which has been placed in a confidential file
<lb/>pursuant to Public Health Law Section 4138.
<lb/>No information shall be released from a record of birth unless the record has been on file for at
<lb/>least 75 years and the person to whom the record relates is known to the applicant to be
<lb/>deceased.
<lb/>No information shall be released from a record of death unless the record has been on file for at
<lb/>least 50 years.
<lb/>No information shall tje released from a record of marriage unless the record has been on file for at
<lb/>least 50 years and the parties to the marriage are known to the applicant to be deceased.
<lb/>The time periods specified in (3B), (3C), and (3D) are waived if the applicant is a descendant or has
<lb/>been designated to act on behalf of a descendant of the person whose record is being
<lb/>requested. A descendant is a person in the direct line of descent. The applicant shall provide
<lb/>documentation of descendancy prior to the release of information in those instances where a
<lb/>waiver of the waiting period is requested. A party acting on behalf of a descendant shall further
<lb/>provide documentation that the descendant authorized the party to make such application.
<lb/>All uncertified copies, abstracts, or information issued for genealogical research purposes shall be
<lb/>clearly marked with the statement "For Genealogical Purposes Only."
<lb/>4. Genealogy Fee Schedule
<lb/>Fee schedule per one spelling of name. Fee varies depending on requested number of years to be
<lb/>searched. Unused fees will be refunded.
<lb/>1-3 years $11.00 31-40 years $51.00
<lb/>4-10 years $21.00 41 -50 years $61.00
<lb/>11 -20 years $31.00 51-00 years $71.00
<lb/>21-30 years $41.00 61-70 years $81.00
<lb/>DON-1562 (10/91) p. 2 of 2
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
