<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>mosher richards brook pine listing 1998</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_richards_1997/mosher_richards_brook_pine_listing_1998/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>mm.
<lb/>41 Brookpine Drive
<lb/>Huntington-Shelton, Ct
<lb/>$ 294,900
<lb/>Style: Colonial, Builder's own home full of thoughtful functional and
<lb/>decorative features, wonderfully situated on a culdesac along with
<lb/>property on 3 sides designated as permanent Open Space by the City of
<lb/>Shelton. The lot is 1.23 acres of treed property with public water
<lb/>supply and private septic system (garden plot in the rear yard is best
<lb/>location for in-ground pool).
<lb/>Home consists of: 8 rms, 4 bedrms, 2.5 baths, full basement with
<lb/>walkout, 2 car garage under with 1 car garage under porch area.
<lb/>3 season enclosed porch, rear deck for cooking grill.
<lb/>• Wonderfully unique masterbedrm. design offers a 1st and 2"^ floor
<lb/>option with access to full baths and big cioset sizes.
<lb/>• Please note some of these special features: Random wide plank
<lb/>pegged floors in kitchen &amp; family rm., 3 French doors (2 pocket
<lb/>style off kitchen). Full crown mldg. in Living &amp; Din. rms. as well as
<lb/>hand crafted beams &amp; base mldg. in family rm.. Solid 6 panel int.
<lb/>doors, numerous ceiling fans, all light fixtures (dining rm. fixture
<lb/>solid brass from Portugal).
<lb/>• Kitchen has Oak cabinets, double sink, built in desk, closet pantry.
<lb/>• Tempered glass used in big window at kitchen table &amp; fixed glass
<lb/>skylite in hallway to porch.
<lb/>•  Skylites in family rm. are opening type with shades.
<lb/>• Rumford fireplace in family rm. has outside air draw venting for
<lb/>efficiency, (Rumford was a compatriot of Ben Franklin who
<lb/>originated a formula for the most efficient firebox configuration,
<lb/>that formula was utilized in the this home's fireplace design.
<lb/>• Exterior windows are longer style thermopane with removable grills.
<lb/>• Main level laundry (storage shelving) in half bath off kitchen.
<lb/>• Oil hot water baseboard heating, 3 zones, interior oil tank.
<lb/>•  200 Amp electrical service, Amway security alarm system on doors.
<lb/>• Automatic garage door opener in front unit only.
<lb/>• Taxes $ 3,347 yearly.
<lb/>• Appliances included: Electric oven-range, microwave, dishwasher.
<lb/>Refrigerator, clothes washer &amp; dryer, all window treatments.
<lb/>• Basement plumbed for additional half bath.
<lb/>Marketed By
<lb/>Paul Jensen, Broker 21 Yrs. Experience
<lb/>William Raveis R.E. 203-929-6388, 924-SOLD (7653)
<lb/>Information herein subject to errors, omission or change.
<lb/>mnm tmts
<lb/>; REAL ESTATE SERVICES i
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
