<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>mosher christopher winthrop society 2001</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_richards_1997/mosher_christopher_winthrop_society_2001/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_richards_1997/mosher_christopher_winthrop_society_2001/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>The WiriTHROP SOCIETY
<lb/>PR/ESERVARE ET TRANSMITTERE
<lb/>John Stimson Beardsley, SECRETARY 2690 Walker Avenue, Carmel, CA 93923
<lb/>4 December, 2001
<lb/>Dear Mr. Mosher
<lb/>Welcome to The Winthrop Society, and thank you for your
<lb/>participation! Exciting things are in the ofOng. As you perhaps know, the
<lb/>Society is construeting a World Wide Web site*, where all family
<lb/>historians may find information about our Society, as well as useful
<lb/>genealogical information for free downloading. We aspire to make it the
<lb/>best resource available on the 'net for early Massachusetts history and
<lb/>genealogy. As a free serviee to our Members, a web page wall be
<lb/>maintamed where you may post queries about your ancestors (limited to
<lb/>pre-1800 birth-dates. New England, New Jersc}^ and New York). The
<lb/>Society will forward responses to the Member who made the postmg.
<lb/>The Society's library has recently made major acquisitions, and we have
<lb/>become a Member Society of the Federation of Genealogical Societies.
<lb/>Promising new soruces of fundmg should soon permit greater services to
<lb/>our Members and the public.
<lb/>Enclosed are your Certificate of Membership £md your first issue of
<lb/>the Winthrop Society Quarterly. Yoiu subscription to fotu issues will run
<lb/>from Volume 2, #3 through Volume 3, #2. Other back issues may be had
<lb/>for ̂ 5 each, subject to availability.
<lb/>We are udshing you and yotu family a very pleasant holiday season!
<lb/>Thanlt you very much for your support!
<lb/>Best regards.
<lb/>* Om- website is at httpi/ATOw.WmthropSociety.org/home.htin
<lb/>We can be reached by e-mail at JSB@WinthropSociety.org
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/>
<lb/>;jj\nTHRoyt&gt;
<lb/>Society"PICfiSERVARE ET TRANSMITTERE"
<lb/>Whereas, Governor John Winthrop and the Puritan families who came to plant the Massachusetts Bay Colony in 1630 were
<lb/>the m
<lb/>o
<lb/>s
<lb/>t
<lb/> important a
<lb/>n
<lb/>d
<lb/> influential g
<lb/>roup
<lb/> of Europeans that ever arrived in North America, the W
<lb/>INTHROP SOCIETY is
<lb/>dedicated to preserving their m
<lb/>emory
<lb/> and tradition, and transmitting their example of courage, strong faith, integrity and civic
<lb/>duty. T
<lb/>h
<lb/>e
<lb/> Society is o
<lb/>p
<lb/>e
<lb/>n
<lb/> to m
<lb/>en and women
<lb/> of good character and proven descent f
<lb/>r
<lb/>o
<lb/>m
<lb/> one or more of the settlers w
<lb/>h
<lb/>o
<lb/>arrived in the Massachusetts B
<lb/>a
<lb/>y
<lb/> before 1633. Therefore, the Society is pleased to w
<lb/>elcome
<lb/> into its m
<lb/>embershipCtlRISTOPtlER ALAM MOStlERin affirmation of his descent fromMr. Nathaniel Turner,
<lb/>a passenger of the W
<lb/>inthrop
<lb/> fleet, 1630.
<lb/>■Dn.oriBy His ExcEtLEKcy
<lb/>'/r^nvyU^k-Ja
<lb/>VaOTimothy
<lb/> L. J
<lb/>acobsPRESIDENTMember #10318, 2 December, 2001
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
