<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Flandreau Graveyard, New Rochelle, New York</title>
                <author>Daughters of the American Revolution</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
                <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
                <date>2019</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <author>Daughters of the American Revolution</author>,
                    <title level="m">Report on Flandreau Graveyard (New Rochelle, New York)</title>, (1941).
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text xml:lang="en">





<body>
<head>FLANDREAU GRAVEYARD</head>
<p>
<lb/>The Flandreau Graveyard was used as a private bural place by the
<lb/>Flandreau family, one of the old Huguenot families of New Rochelle.
<lb/>The farm on which the burial plot was established was owned by Peter
<lb/>Flandreau, and devised by him to his brother, Benjamin, in his will, dated
<lb/>April 20, 1785. It is just possible that the burial place was started by
<lb/>Peter, but this is not definitely known. The stone of Benjamin Flandreau
<lb/>who died February 19, 1800, is believed to be the oldest in the cemetery
<lb/>and his burial in the plot is believed to be the first. It is stated by
<lb/>Mr. Morgan H. Seacord that when he made a record of the inscription on
<lb/>this stone, over forty years ago, it was the oldest in the cemetery. The
<lb/>stone may still be found and read, although it is lying out of place on
<lb/>the ground under leaves and branches.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>The plot was not laid out by deed until February 16, 1814, when the
<lb/>children of Benjamin Flandreau made a reservation 28 yards by 13 yards,
<lb/>with a right-of-way for access thereto from Boston Post Road of Turnpike
<lb/>Road. (Libre "R", page 200, White Plains Court House) Between the time
<lb/>of the burial of Benjamin Flandreau (1800) and the time the plot was
<lb/>formally laid out (1814) there had been burials by other members of the
<lb/>Flandreau family.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>The cemetery is still owned by the heirs of the Benjamin Flandreau who
<lb/>died on February 19, 1800. It is apparently abandoned, with no one left
<lb/>who is interested in its care. Most of the names on the stones are those
<lb/>of old and respected Huguenot families of New Rochelle.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>The cemetery - or what is left of it - is located on Chester Place, just
<lb/>east of Emerson Avenue. Emerson Avenue is at the east end of Main Street
<lb/>or the Boston Post Road, and runs from Main Street towards the Sound.
<lb/>Chester Place is the second street to the left, off of Emerson, (see map)
<lb/>The east line of the cemetery is right on the boundary line between New
<lb/>Rochelle and Mamaroneck.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>This farm was purchased some time before the Civil War by Samuel F.
<lb/>Cowdrey. He called the place "Hazelhurst", a name still used for the
<lb/>section. The burial plot was not included in the purchase of the farm by
<lb/>Mr. Cowdrey. A right-of-way to the plot was also retained by the Flandreau
<lb/>family. Mr. Cowdrey wanted the property as a part of his estate. He
<lb/>therefore offered to buy the plot and move, at his own expense, all of
<lb/>the bodies to a burial ground selected by the Flandreau heirs. They were
<lb/>unwilling to agree to this, for the little graveyard was still being used
<lb/>and carefully cared for. Mr. Cowdrey had a hedge planted around the plot
<lb/>and it was also enclosed by a stone wall. After the death of Mr. Cowdrey,
<lb/>in the late years of the 19th centrury, the property was taken over and
<lb/>development of it as a residential park started some forty years ago.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>The plot has not been used for burial for many years. About 1889 Mr.
<lb/>George T. Davis wrote a paper on the cemeteries of New Rochelle. About
<lb/>the Flandreau Graveyard he says:
<quote>
    <lb/>"This cemetery is situated on Main Street at the Mamaroneck line
    <lb/>east of the residence of Mr. S. F. Cowdrey and can not be seen
    <lb/>from the street. No persons except the Flandreau family are buried
    <lb/>here. The interments average about one per year. Only one monument
    <lb/>is erected here and that was erected to the memory of a young man
    <lb/>who was killed during the war."
</quote>
</p>
<p>
<lb/>There could not have been many burials after this time, although there was
<lb/>an inscription on a stone recorded in 1923 indicating a burial in 1892.
<lb/>This burial was very likely the last. After the opening of Beechwoods
<lb/>cemetery there were many removals from this old private plot to the new
<lb/>cemetery.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>The monument of which Mr. Davis speaks was erected during the Civil War
<lb/>by the parents of Elisha Harsen. On May 10, 1923. Mrs. Florence S. Bennett
<lb/>of New Rochelle visited this cemetery. At that time the development of
<lb/>the locality was going forward, new roads were being put through, houses
<lb/>were being built, etc. Mrs. Bennett found the little cemetery in a deplor-
<lb/>able condition. However, at that time the monument to Elisha Harsen was
<lb/>still intact, except for small shippings. She made a copy of the very
<lb/>interesting inscription, which follows:
<quote>
    <lb/>             In
    <lb/>          Memory of
    <lb/>        Elisha Harsen
    <lb/>    aged 23 yrs. and 4 mos.
    <lb/>1st Asst. Engineer in the United
    <lb/>States Navy on board the Monitor
    <lb/>Tecumseh, who perished in Mobile
    <lb/>Bay on Aug. 5th, 1864, when their
    <lb/>vessel was sunk by a rebel torpe-
    <lb/>do,  This monument is erected by
    <lb/>his parents whose consolation is,
    <lb/>that their son died in the ser-
    <lb/>vice of his country.  He died do-
    <lb/>ing what he could to suppress the
    <lb/>wicked rebellion of the slave
    <lb/>states.  While leading the fleet
    <lb/>which ran past the forts of Mobile
    <lb/>Bay, the Tecumseh was struck by
    <lb/>the fatal torpedo which launched
    <lb/>into eternity as brave a crew as
    <lb/>ever manned a vessel.  They offer-
    <lb/>ed themselves a sacrifice to their
    <lb/>country, met the fate they had
    <lb/>some reason to expect, and by
    <lb/>bravely confronting it, averted
    <lb/>it from others.  None but heros
    <lb/>would have consented to lead
    <lb/>through the terrible dangers of
    <lb/>that battle day.  As heros they
    <lb/>did their duty; while at their
    <lb/>ports they perished and were bur-
    <lb/>ied in the dark waters with more
    <lb/>that a hero's salute.  Their
    <lb/>country will never cease to cher-
    <lb/>ish the fame they so gallantly won.
</quote>
<lb/>This inscription occupies three sides of the monument. On the forth side
<lb/>is the following quotation:
<quote>
<lb/>"DULCE ET DECORUM EST PRO PATRIA MORI"
</quote>
</p>
<p>
<lb/>A week later a second visit was made and Mrs. Bennett found that the shaft
<lb/>of monument had been forced off of the base, and an effort had appar-
<lb/>ently been made to destroy it. As a result of the story which Mrs. Bennett
<lb/>wrote and which was published in the "Standard-Star" the monument was moved
<lb/>to Beechwoods Cemetery where it may now be seen.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>Another Civil War soldier, buried in this plot, was Theodore Flandreau, a
<lb/>sergeant. His stone was so broken at the time Mrs. Bennett visited the
<lb/>cemetery that nothing more could be read. However, his record was known,
<lb/>and a stone to his memory now stands in the Beechwoods Cemetery not far
<lb/>from that of Elisha Harsen. Theodore Flandreau was the son of Elijah
<lb/>Flandreau. He was born on July 5, 1844. He served in Company E. 73rd
<lb/>N.Y. Volunteer Infantry. He died on Nov. 20, 1886. The "Flandreau Post"
<lb/>G.A.R. is named in honor of him and of his brother, John.
</p>
<p>
<lb/>The little cemetery is now in even worse condition, few of the stones are
<lb/>legible, and fewer still are in their original positions. Scattered
<lb/>pieces of markers were found in all parts of the plot. An attempt was made
<lb/>to fit them together. It was sometimes possible to do this. However, it
<lb/>was impossible to locate the positions of the graves. Therefore, no sat-
<lb/>isfactory map of the graveyard can be furnished.
</p>
<lb/>
<list>
<head><lb/>FLANDREAU GRAVEYARD</head>
<item>
<lb/> 1. A miscellaneous groups of fallen stones. It was not possible to read
<lb/>    any of them. They were on a line with the rear of the plot where the
<lb/>    tabulation started.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 2. FLANDREAU
<lb/>In memory of ELIZABETH, wife of BENJAMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>who died September 15, 1822.  Aged 51.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 3. FLANDREAU
<lb/>In memory of ....AMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>who departed this life Aug. 27th, 1807.
<lb/>Aged 45 years, 2 months &amp; 10 days.
<lb/>Foot Stone B.F.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 5. FLANDREAU
<lb/>SUSAN FLANDREAU
<lb/>Died Nov. 5, 1868.
<lb/>Aged 68 years, 2 months and 12 days.
<lb/>Stone in good condition.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 6. Broken Stone.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 7. Broken Stone.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 8. SEACORD
<lb/>In memory of MAGDALEN, wife of DANIEL SEACORD
<lb/>who died Jan. 30, 1840.
<lb/>Aged 80 years, 4 months and 1 day.
</item>
<item>
<lb/> 9. SEACORD
<lb/>In memory of JOHN W. SEACORD, son of DANIEL
<lb/>who died July 10, 1838. Aged 41 years.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>10. RUSSEL
<lb/>SARAH ESTHER, daughter of (LABAN?) &amp; SARAH RUSSEL
<lb/>departed this life Oct. 16, 1829 in her 15th year.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>11. Fallen Stone.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>12. SEACORD
<lb/>In memory of JAMES A., son of
<lb/>LEONARD and MARIA SEACORD
<lb/>who died Oct. 13th, 1842. Aged 5 yrs. and 5 mos.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>13. Group of eight field stone markers.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>14. FLANDREAU
<lb/>In Memory of BENJAMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>who departed this life February 19, 1800.
<lb/>Aged 81 years, 5 months and 15 days.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>15. The G
<lb/>DANIEL
<lb/>BO
<lb/>Nothing more could be read.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>16. FLANDREAU
<lb/>In memory of ANN ELIZA, wife of BENJAMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>who died Mar. 4, 1835. Agen 24 years, 2 mo. 23 days.
<lb/>also
<lb/>BENJAMIN FLANDREAU, son of
<lb/>BENJAMIN and ANN ELIZA FLANDREAU
<lb/>died Mar. 25, 1835. Aged 1 month &amp; 12 days.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>17. FLANDREAU
<lb/>In memory of BENJAMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>Born Feb. 22, 1810. Died Nov. 21, 1844.
<lb/>Foot Stone B.F.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>18. MULLINEX
<lb/>In memory of JOSEPH MULLINEX
<lb/>who departed this life Oct. the 28th day, 1807.
<lb/>Aged 83 years, 1 month, 13 days.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>19. Foot Stone D.S.
<lb/>(DANIEL SECORD'S stone was standing in 1923.
<lb/>See below.)
</item>
<item>
<lb/>20. Miscellaneous group of 20 or more markers. No inscriptions
<lb/>could be read at this time.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>21. FLANDREAU
<lb/>In memory of CATHARINE IRENE, wife of
<lb/>Elder DANIEL A. FLANDREAU
<lb/>who departed this life October 8th, 1815.
<lb/>Aged 40 years and 23 days.
<lb/>Foot Stone C.I.F.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>22 ISABELLE
<lb/>Nothing more could be read on this stone at this
<lb/>time (See below for record of 1923.)
</item>
</list>


<list>
<head>
<lb/>Note 1. Over forty years ago Mr. Morgan H. Seacord, well-known historian
<lb/>of New Rochelle and descendant of an old Huguenot family made a partial
<lb/>record of grave stomes in the Flandreau Graveyard at that time. The
<lb/>following inscriptions, not found in 1939, were recorded by him.
</head>
<item>
<lb/>In memory of ESTHER FLANDREAU
<lb/>the wife of BENJAMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>who departed this life May 8th, 1811.
<lb/>in the 82nd year of her age.
<lb/>(She ws ESTHER BADEAU. Red Stone.)
<lb/>On the bottom of stone recorded above as No. 3.
<lb/>Also of his son BENJAMIN, who departed this life
<lb/>August 20th, 1805. Aged 1 year, 10 months &amp; 7 days.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>In Memory of JOHN FLANDREAU, who departed this life
<lb/>January 27th, 1809, Aged 37 years, 9 months &amp; 25 days.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>In Memory of ELIZABETH, wife of BENJAMIN FLANDREAU
<lb/>who died Sept. 15, 1822, AE. 51
</item>
<item>
<lb/>Sacred to the memory of ESTHER, widow of WILLIAM STILLWELL
<lb/>who died April 26th, 1832, in the 76th year of her age.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>The Grave of DANIEL SECORD
<lb/>Born March 13, 1759. Died June 13, 1843.
<lb/>(See 15 and 19 above.)
</item>
<item>
<lb/>In Memory of of MAGDALEN, wife of DANIEL SECORD
<lb/>who died Jan. 30, 1840. Aged 80 years 4 months &amp; 1 day.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>In Memory of JOHN W. SEACORD, son of
<lb/>DANIEL and MAGDALEN SEACORD
<lb/>who died July 10, 1838. Aged 41 yrs. 1 mo. and 12 days.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>JOHN BADEAU, died Dec. 11, 1815. Aged 74 years.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>SUSAN BADEAU, died Dec. 8, 1817. Aged 66 years.
</item>
</list>

<list>
<head>
<lb/>Note 2. In 1923 Mrs. Florence S. Bennett of New Rochelle visitied this
<lb/>cemetery and made as much of a record as she could. The cemetery was,
<lb/>at that time, filled with litter of the development which was going
<lb/>on all around it. The following stones not found in 1939, were record-
<lb/>er by her at that time.
</head>
<item>
<lb/>ESTHER FLANDREAU, wife, died May 8, 1811, Age 82.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>BENJAMIN FLANDREAU, died Sept. 13, 1822. Age 54.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>BENJAMIN FLANDREAU, died 1832. Age 51.
</item>
<item>
<lb/>ISABELLE FLANDREAU, wife, died Nov. 19, 1892. Age 82.
<lb/>(See No. 22)
</item>
<item>
<lb/>DANIEL SEACORD, died 1843. Age 84. (See No. 19)
</item>
<item>
<lb/>JOHN SEACORD, son, died April 26, 1832. Age ?
</item>
</list>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
