<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>mosher fred ssa records</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-002" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-002.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-003" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-003.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-004" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-004.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-005" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-005.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-006" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-006.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-007" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-007.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-008" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-008.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-009" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-009.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-010" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_fred_ssa_records/p-010.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>REQUEST FOR SOCIAL SECURITY EARNINGS INFORMATION
<lb/>Form Approved
<lb/>0MB No. 0960-0525
<lb/>Form SSA-7050-F4 (2-96) (Formerly SSA-7050-F3 Destroy prior editions) Printed on recycled paper
<lb/>2. Certified Yearly Totals of Earnings
<lb/>Includes total earnings for each year but does not include
<lb/>the names and addresses of employers.
<lb/>PRIVACY ACT NOTICE: We are authorized to collect this information under section 205 of the Social Security Act, and the Federal Records Act of 1 950
<lb/>(64 Stat. 583). It is needed so we can identify your records and prepare the statement you request. Vou do not have to furnish the information, but failure
<lb/>to do so may prevent your request from being processec^.
<lb/>The Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995 requires us to notify.You that this information collection is in accordance vvith the clearance requirements of
<lb/>section 3507 of the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995. We may not conduct or sponsor, and you are not required to respond to, a collection of
<lb/>InformatiorMjnless it displays a valid .t. —
<lb/>TIME IT TAKES TO COMPLETE THIS FORM
<lb/>We estimate that it will take you about 11 minutes to com]
<lb/>facts and fill out the form. If you have comments or suggestions on
<lb/>Officer; l-A-21 Operations BIdg., Baltimore, MD 21235-0001. Send only comments relating to our
<lb/>requests for Social Security cards and other claims-related Information should be sent to your Iccc!
<lb/>Social Security Administration In the U.S. Government section of your telepjione^directonn
<lb/>INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR REQUEST
<lb/>iplete this form. This includes the time it will take to read the instructions, gather the necessary
<lb/>this estimate, write to the Social Security Administration, ATTN: Reports Clearance
<lb/>z-r "time It takes" estimate to the office listed above. All
<lb/>local Social Security office, whose address Is listed under
<lb/>*Use This Form If You Need
<lb/>1. Certified/Non-Certified Detailed Earnings Information
<lb/>includes periods of employment or self-employment and the
<lb/>names and addresses of employers.
<lb/>How Do I Get This Information?
<lb/>You need to complete the attached form to tell
<lb/>us what information you want.
<lb/>Can I Get This Information For Someone Else?
<lb/>Yes, if you have their written permission. For
<lb/>more information, see page 3.
<lb/>Who Can Sign On Behalf Of The Individual?
<lb/>The parent of a minor child, or the legal guardian
<lb/>of an individual who has been declared legally
<lb/>incompetent, may sign if he/she is acting on
<lb/>behalf of the individual.
<lb/>Is There A Fee For This Information?
<lb/>1. Certified/IMon-Certified-Detailed
<lb/>Earnings Information
<lb/>i^ally charge a fee for detailedYes, we u3|ially charge a fee for detailed
<lb/>information. In most cases, this information
<lb/>is used for purposes NOT directly related to
<lb/>Social Security such as for a private ^
<lb/>pension plan or personal injury suit. The fee
<lb/>chart on page 3 gives the amount of the
<lb/>charge.
<lb/>Sometimes, there is no charge for detailed
<lb/>information. If you have reason to believe
<lb/>your earnings are not correct (for example,
<lb/>you have previously received earnings
<lb/>information from us and it does not agree
<lb/>with your records), we will supply you with
<lb/>more detail for the period in question.
<lb/>Occasionally, earnings amounts are wrong
<lb/>because an employer did not correctly
<lb/>2. Certified Yearly Totals of Earnings
<lb/>Yes, there is a fee of $15 to certify yearly
<lb/>totals of earnings. Certification is usually not
<lb/>necessary unless you plan to use the
<lb/>Information in court.
<lb/>3. Method of Payment
<lb/>Enclose a check or money order for the entire
<lb/>fee required. Payment can also be made by
<lb/>credit card. To do so, complete page 4 of this
<lb/>form and return it with your request form.
<lb/>• Can The Fee Be Waived or Reduced?
<lb/>Yes, if you show that giving the information to
<lb/>you will benefit the general public. Send your
<lb/>explanation with this form to the Freedom of
<lb/>Information Officer, Social Security
<lb/>Administration, Baltimore, Maryland 21235.
<lb/>DO NOT USE THIS FORM FOR;
<lb/>Non-certified yearly totals of earnings
<lb/>This service is free to the public.
<lb/>These totals can be obtained by dalling '
<lb/>1-800-772-1213 to receive Form SSA-7004,
<lb/>Request for Earnings and Benefit Estimate
<lb/>Statement.
<lb/>report earnings or earnings are credited to
<lb/>the wrong person. In situations like these,
<lb/>we will send you detailed information, at no
<lb/>charge, so we can correct your record.
<lb/>Be sure to show the year(s) involved on the
<lb/>request form and explain why you need the
<lb/>information. If you do not tell us why you
<lb/>need the information, we will charge a fee.
<lb/>We will certify the detailed earnings
<lb/>information for an additional fee of $15.00.
<lb/>Certification is usually not necessary unless
<lb/>you plan to use the information in court.
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/>
<lb/>1. From whose record do you need the earnings Information?
<lb/>Print the Name, Social Security Number (SSN), and date of birth below.
<lb/>Your Reference Number
<lb/>h  Colviio
<lb/>Social Security , , / ^ ̂
<lb/>Number OOgb
<lb/>Other Name(s) Used
<lb/>(Include Maiden Name)
<lb/>2. What kind of information do you need?
<lb/>Detailed Earnings Information I
<lb/>(If you check this block, tell us befevw
<lb/>why you need this information.)
<lb/>$bAR CH
<lb/>Date of Birth
<lb/>For the period(s) / year(s):
<lb/>CH Certified Total Earnings For Each Year. For the year(s):
<lb/>(Check this box only if you want the information
<lb/>certified. Otherwise, call 1-800-772-1213
<lb/>to request Form SSA-7004, Request for Earnings
<lb/>and Benefit Estimate Statement)
<lb/>3. If you owe us a fee for this detailed earnings information, enter the amount due
<lb/>using the chart on page A $
<lb/>Do you want us to certify the information? Cj! Yes 0
<lb/>If yes, enter $15.00 ... . B
<lb/>ADD the amounts on lines A and B, and
<lb/>enter the TOTAL amount
<lb/>^ Loo
<lb/>Lo o
<lb/>•  You can pay by CREDIT CARD by completing and returning the form on page 4, or
<lb/>•  Send your (3HECK or MONEY ORDER for the amount on line C with the request
<lb/>and make check or money order payable to "Social Security Administration."
<lb/>•  DO NOT SEND CASH.
<lb/>4. I am the individud to whom the record pertains (or a person who is authorized to sign on behalf of that individual). I
<lb/>understand that ̂ y false representation to knowingly and willfully obtain information from Social Security records is
<lb/>punishable by a fine of not more than $5,000 or one year in prison.
<lb/>^^ p..
<lb/>SIGN your name here I I
<lb/>(Do not print) &gt; /X s Date j?/ l&amp;fl&amp;cxo
<lb/>5. Tell us where you want the information sent. (Please print)
<lb/>Name Mo &lt; H sf-
<lb/>Address U\ pt/yg pR
<lb/>6. Mail Completed Form(s) To:
<lb/>Social Security Administration
<lb/>Office of Central Records Operations
<lb/>P.O. Box 129
<lb/>Baltimore, Maryland 21235
<lb/>City, State &amp; ZIP Code $HE&gt;-TohJ CT Q i "4 gH
<pb n="3" facs="#page-002"/>
<lb/>REQUEST FOR SOCIAL SECURITY EARNINGS INFORMATION
<lb/>How Much Do I Have To Pay For Detailed Earnings?
<lb/>1- Count the number of years for which you need detailed earnings information. Be sure to add in both the first and
<lb/>last year requested. However, do not add in the current calendar year since this information is not yet available.
<lb/>2. Use the chart below to determine the correct fee.
<lb/>Number of Years
<lb/>Requested
<lb/>Number of Years
<lb/>Requested
<lb/>Number of Years
<lb/>Requested
<lb/>$15.00
<lb/>17.50 'n t
<lb/>20.00
<lb/>22.50
<lb/>25.00
<lb/>27.00
<lb/>29.00
<lb/>31.00
<lb/>33.00
<lb/>35.00
<lb/>36.75
<lb/>38.50
<lb/>40.25
<lb/>42.00
<lb/>$43.75
<lb/>45.50
<lb/>47.25
<lb/>49.00
<lb/>50.75
<lb/>52.50
<lb/>54.00
<lb/>55.50
<lb/>57.00
<lb/>58.50
<lb/>60.00
<lb/>61.50
<lb/>63.00 40 ''I
<lb/>$64.50
<lb/>66.00
<lb/>67.50
<lb/>68.75
<lb/>70.00
<lb/>71.25
<lb/>72.50
<lb/>73.75
<lb/>75.00
<lb/>76.25
<lb/>77.50
<lb/>78.75
<lb/>80.00
<lb/>For Requests Over 40 Years, Please Add 1 Dollar For Each Additional Year.
<lb/>• Whose Earnings Can Be Requested?
<lb/>1. Your Earning
<lb/>You can request earnings information from your own
<lb/>record by completing the attached form; we need your
<lb/>handwritten signature. If you sign with an "X", your
<lb/>mark must be witnessed by two disinterested persons
<lb/>who must sign their name and address.
<lb/>2. Someone Else's Earnings
<lb/>You can request earnings information from the record
<lb/>of someone else if that person tells us in writing to give
<lb/>the information to you. This writing or "authorization"
<lb/>must be presented to us within 60 days of the date it
<lb/>was signed by that person.
<lb/>3. A Deceased Person's Earnings
<lb/>You can request earnings information from the record
<lb/>of a deceased person if you are the legal representative
<lb/>of the estate, a survivor (that is, the spouse, parent,
<lb/>child, divorced spouse or divorced parent), or an
<lb/>individual with a material interest (example - financial)
<lb/>who is an heir at law, next of kin, beneficiary under the
<lb/>will or donee of property of the decedent.
<lb/>Proof of death must be included with your request.
<lb/>Proof of appointment as representative or proof of your
<lb/>relationship to the deceased must also be included.
<pb n="4" facs="#page-003"/>
<lb/>YOU CAN MAKE YOUR PAYMENT BY CREDIT CARD
<lb/>As a convenience, we offer you the option to make your payment by credit card. However, regular credit card rules will apply.
<lb/>You may also pay by check or money order.
<lb/>We Only Accept MasterCard and VISA
<lb/>Please fill in all the information below and return this form along with your request to;
<lb/>Social Security Administration
<lb/>Office of Central Records Operations
<lb/>P.O. Box 129
<lb/>Baltimore, Maryland 21235
<lb/>Note: Ploasefread Paperwork/Privacy Act Notice
<lb/>NUMBER HOLDER'S SSN
<lb/>{If more than one request, only list one SSN)
<lb/>CHECK ONE MasterCard □ VISA □
<lb/>Credit Card Holder's Name
<lb/>{Enter the name from the credit card)
<lb/>Credit Card Holder's Address
<lb/>Daytime Telephone Number
<lb/>First, Middle Initial, Last Name
<lb/>Number &amp; Street
<lb/>City, State, Zip Code
<lb/>Amount Charged $
<lb/>Telephone Number
<lb/>Credit Card Number
<lb/>Credit Card Expiration Date
<lb/>Year
<lb/>Credit Card Holder's Signature
<lb/>DO NOT WRITE IN THIS SPACE
<lb/>OFFICE USE ONLY &gt;
<lb/>Authorisation
<lb/>Name
<lb/>PAPERWORK/PRIVACY ACT NOTICE
<lb/>The Social Security Administration (SSA) has authority to collect the information requested on this form under section
<lb/>205 of the Social Security Act. Giving us this information is voluntary. You do not have to do it. We will need this
<lb/>information only if you choose to make payment by credit card. You do not need to fill out this form if you choose
<lb/>another means of payment (for example, by check or money order).
<lb/>If you choose the credit card payment option, we will provide the information you give us to the banks handling your
<lb/>credit card account and SSA's account. We may also provide this information to another person or government agency
<lb/>to comply with federal laws requiring the release of information from our records. You can find these and other routine
<lb/>uses of information provided to SSA listed in the Federal Register. If you want more information about this, you may call
<lb/>or write any Social Security Office.
<lb/>Form SSA-7050-F4 (2-96) *U.S. Government Printing Office: 1996 - 404-816/40034
<pb n="5" facs="#page-004"/>
<lb/>Social Security Administration
<lb/>Retirement, Survivors and Disability Insurance
<lb/>Earnings Record Information
<lb/>From: Office of Central Operations
<lb/>300 North Greene Street, Baltimore, Maryland 21201
<lb/>FREDERICK C MOSHER
<lb/>41 BROOK PINE DR
<lb/>SHELTON CT 06484
<lb/>Date: "JUN 29 2000
<lb/>Refer to: S2RB1A/
<lb/>Your Reference:
<lb/>We are sending you the statement of earnings you requested for the number holder shown below.
<lb/>Number Holder's Name:
<lb/>FREDERICK C MOSHER
<lb/>Social Security Number:
<lb/>116-05-0086
<lb/>If we recently received earnings information, it may not yet be shown on this statement.
<lb/>Please read the back of this letter for more information about Social Security records.
<lb/>If you have any questions, you should call, write or visit any social Security office. If you visit,
<lb/>please bring this letter. It will help us answer questions.
<lb/>Enclosures:
<lb/>Original Letter
<lb/>Earnings Statement
<lb/>Control Number:
<lb/>Remittance CTL Number:
<lb/>Department of Health and Human Services
<lb/>Social Security Administration
<lb/>Form SSA-L460 (4-91) Destroy Prior Editions
<pb n="6" facs="#page-005"/>
<lb/>INFORMATION ABOUT SOCIAL SECURITY RECORDS
<lb/>Our records show the amount of earnings reported, not the amount of Social Security taxes
<lb/>which were paid.
<lb/>Wages were first covered under Social Security in 1937. Therefore, 1937 is the first year for
<lb/>which earnings may be shown on our records. Employers were required to report earnings
<lb/>semi-annually in 1937, and on a quarterly basis for the years from 1938 through 1977.
<lb/>Beginning with 1978, employers are required to report earnings annually.
<lb/>Our records do not show the exact dates of employment (month and day) because we don't
<lb/>need this information to figure Social Security benefits. Employers do not give us this
<lb/>information.
<lb/>Our records may not show earnings from last year because it takes some time to process
<lb/>earnings reports from employers.
<lb/>Each year, there is a maximum amount of earnings which are subject to Social Security taxes
<lb/>and are used to compute benefits. If a person earns more than this maximum amount, the
<lb/>earnings statement will usually show the maximum rather than the total earnings.
<lb/>Maximum Yearly
<lb/>Earnings Taxed
<lb/>for Social Security Years
<lb/>Maximum Yearly
<lb/>Earnings Taxed
<lb/>for Social Security
<lb/>$ 3,000
<lb/>$ 3,600
<lb/>$ 4,200
<lb/>$ 4,800
<lb/>$ 6,600
<lb/>$ 7,800
<lb/>$ 9,000
<lb/>$10,800
<lb/>$13,200
<lb/>$14,100
<lb/>$15,300
<lb/>$16,500
<lb/>$17,700
<lb/>$22,900
<lb/>$25,900
<lb/>$29,700
<lb/>$32,400
<lb/>$35,700
<lb/>$37,800
<lb/>$39,600
<lb/>$42,000
<lb/>$43,800
<lb/>$45,000
<lb/>$48,000
<lb/>$51,300
<lb/>•  Beginning in 1951, self-employed persons could also receive Social Security credit for their
<lb/>work. The maximum amounts of self-employment earnings that are subject to Social
<lb/>Security taxes and are used to compute benefits are the same as those shown above.
<lb/>[] Please read the enclosed pamphlet(s) for more information.
<lb/>•  In 1991, the maximum yearly earnings taxed for Hospital Insurance is $125,000.
<lb/>Form SSA-L460 (4-91)
<pb n="001" facs="#page-006"/>
<lb/>SSA-1826 ITEMIZED STATEMENT OF EARNINGS
<lb/>VERSION 1984.002 * * * FOR SSN 116-05-0086 ^
<lb/>FROM: SOCIAL SECURITY ADMINISTRATION
<lb/>OFFICE OF CENTRAL RECORDS OPERATIONS
<lb/>BALTIMORE, MARYLAND 21235-0000
<lb/>FREDERICK MOSHER
<lb/>41 BROOK PINE DRIVE
<lb/>NUMBER HOLDER NAME
<lb/>FREDERICK C MOSHER
<lb/>SHELTON CT 06484
<lb/>PERIOD REQUESTED JANUARY 1937 THRU DECEMBER 1992
<lb/>YEAR JAN - MARCH APRIL -JUNE JULY - SEPT OCT - DEC
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0273440
<lb/>COLGATE INN INC
<lb/>PAYNE NY 00000-0000
<lb/>1937 104.05 41.55 $
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 94-0313318
<lb/>BECHTEL PRICE CALLAHAN
<lb/>220 BUSH ST
<lb/>SAN FRANCISCO CA 00000-0000
<lb/>1943
<lb/>1944 406.50
<lb/>1 ,339.88 1 ,599.31 1 ,298.81 $
<lb/>$
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 94-0295280
<lb/>GUY F ATKINSON CO
<lb/>1001 BAYHILL DR 2ND FLR
<lb/>SAN BRUNO CA 94066-3061
<lb/>1944 1 ,293.00
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0527427
<lb/>JOHN J HARVEY CO INC
<lb/>496 FRENCH RD
<lb/>UTICA NY 13502-0000
<lb/>1953 48. 18
<lb/>595.50
<lb/>PAGE 001
<pb n="002" facs="#page-007"/>
<lb/>SSA-1826 ITEMIZED STATEMENT OF EARNINGS
<lb/>VERSION 1984.002 * * * FOR SSN 116-05-0086 * * *
<lb/>YEAR JAN - MARCH APRIL -JUNE JULY - SEPT OCT - DEC
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 13-1522353
<lb/>CONSOLIDATED CONSTRUCTORS INC -DEL-
<lb/>616 CONGRESS ST
<lb/>PORTLAND ME 04101-0000
<lb/>1953
<lb/>1958
<lb/>1959
<lb/>1 ,560.00
<lb/>1 ,560.00
<lb/>1 ,690.00
<lb/>1 ,690.00
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 04-1758595
<lb/>EDMUND J RAPPOLI CO
<lb/>515 MOSS AVE
<lb/>CAMBRIDGE MA 00000-0000
<lb/>714.18
<lb/>950.00
<lb/>910.00
<lb/>225.60 $
<lb/>1954 347.88
<lb/>15-0238325EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0238325
<lb/>FA BALLARD
<lb/>FRED BALLARD CONSTRUCTION CO
<lb/>320 BRIDGE ST
<lb/>SOLVAY NY 13209-0000
<lb/>1 ,386.00 396.00 $
<lb/>1954 811.63 $
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 04-2042955
<lb/>BEACON CONST CO OF MASS INC
<lb/>102 HANO ST
<lb/>ALLSTON MA 02134-0000
<lb/>1955 193.88
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 11-0629257
<lb/>CLAYBURN CONTRACTING CORP
<lb/>3 HUNTER ST
<lb/>LONG ISLANDCITY NY 11101-0000
<lb/>1955 845.00
<lb/>PAGE 002
<pb n="003" facs="#page-008"/>
<lb/>SSA-1826 ITEMIZED STATEMENT OF EARNINGS
<lb/>VERSION 1984.002 * * * FOR SSN 116-05-0086 * * *
<lb/>YEAR JAN - MARCH APRIL -JUNE JULY - SEPT OCT - DEC
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0528258
<lb/>D H FELLOWS CONSTRUCTION CORP
<lb/>PO BOX 98
<lb/>MINOA NY 13116-0000
<lb/>1955
<lb/>1956
<lb/>23.00
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 13-1790095
<lb/>INGARDIA CONSTRUCTION CO INC
<lb/>26 EAST 1ST ST
<lb/>MOUNT VERNON NY 10550-0000
<lb/>1955
<lb/>1956 51 .75
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0348537
<lb/>IRISH CONSTRUCTION CO INC
<lb/>205 ONEIDA ST
<lb/>SYRACUSE NY 13202-0000
<lb/>1956 670.86
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 13-5493340
<lb/>VENATOR GROUP SPECIALTY INC
<lb/>% PAYROLL TAX &amp; ACCOUNTING
<lb/>PO BOX 2663
<lb/>HARRISBURG PA 17105-2663
<lb/>1956
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0515302
<lb/>MCKAY CONSTRUCTION CO INC
<lb/>1 12 FARRIER AVE
<lb/>ONEIDA NY 13421-0000
<lb/>1956
<lb/>1957 1 ,440.00 1 ,680.00
<lb/>1 ,567.45
<lb/>902.00
<lb/>762.85 $
<lb/>1 ,030.25 $
<lb/>720.00
<lb/>1 ,080.00
<lb/>148.00 $
<lb/>PAGE 003
<pb n="004" facs="#page-010"/>
<lb/>SSA-1826 ITEMIZED STATEMENT OF EARNINGS
<lb/>VERSION 1984.002 * * * FOR SSN 116-05-0086
<lb/>YEAR JAN - MARCH APRIL -JUNE JULY - SEPT OCT - DEC TOTAL
<lb/>EMPLOYER NUMBER: 15-0570311
<lb/>BERSANI REALTY &amp; CONSTRUCTION INC
<lb/>700 E WATER ST
<lb/>SYRACUSE NY 13210-0000
<lb/>1 ,505.00
<lb/>4,800.002,275.00 2,275.00 250.00
<lb/>SELF EMPLOYMENT
<lb/>2,570.17
<lb/>1  ,971.74
<lb/>2,620.77
<lb/>1  ,855.00
<lb/>1  ,965.00
<lb/>481 .00
<lb/>2,857.00
<lb/>2,964.00
<lb/>3,303.00
<lb/>702.00
<lb/>3, 156.00
<lb/>596.00
<lb/>3,005.00
<lb/>2,182.00
<lb/>871 .00
<lb/>PAGE 004
<pb n="005" facs="#page-009"/>
<lb/>SSA-1826 ITEMIZED STATEMENT OF EARNINGS
<lb/>VERSION 1984.002 * * * FOR SSN 116-05-0086 ^
<lb/>YEAR JAN - MARCH APRIL -JUNE JULY - SEPT OCT - DEC
<lb/>1971
<lb/>1972
<lb/>1978
<lb/>1981
<lb/>1982
<lb/>1983
<lb/>1984
<lb/>1985
<lb/>OUR RECORDS DO NOT SHOW THE AMOUNT OF EARNINGS IN EACH QUARTER
<lb/>OF 1937 BECAUSE EMPLOYERS WERE REQUIRED TO FILE REPORTS ONLY TWICE
<lb/>IN THAT YEAR
<lb/>THERE ARE NO OTHER EARNINGS RECORDED UNDER THIS SOCIAL SECURITY
<lb/>NUMBER FOR THE PERIOD(S) REQUESTED.
<lb/>EARNINGS FOR THE YEARS AFTER 1998 MAY NOT BE SHOWN, OR ONLY
<lb/>PARTIALLY SHOWN, BECAUSE THEY MAY NOT YET BE ON OUR RECORDS.
<lb/>PAGE 005 END
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
