<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>mosher 45 n main earlville</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-002" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-002.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-003" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-003.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-004" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-004.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-005" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-005.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-006" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-006.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-007" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-007.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-008" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-008.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-009" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-009.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-010" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-010.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-011" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/mosher_harrison/mosher_45_n_main_earlville/p-011.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>€mnt^ (^xxix^u^tt as in ®ax:es
<lb/>OWNER hXeXX^. B ̂;L.dj^i.n,
<lb/>STATE OF NEW YORK
<lb/>COUNTY OF MADISON
<lb/>ss.
<lb/>I, Alvin J. White, Treasurer of the county of Madison, State of New York, do HEREBY
<lb/>CERTIFY that as such official I am custodian and have charge of the records and files in this
<lb/>office relating to taxes, tax sales and unredeemed tax sales; that I have caused examination and
<lb/>search of such records and files to be made this day, covering the period from 7.?.....
<lb/>to date and find no unpaid taxes against or tax sales affecting the property known and described
<lb/>as:
<lb/>Baldwin, Aletta, Res., h5 North Main St., Bounded N. by Morgan, E. by Main St.,
<lb/>S. by M. S. Parsonage, W. by Hinckley, Dist. 2, Val. $2250.
<lb/>Except as follows: N one.
<lb/>While the undersigned has endeavored to insure
<lb/>accuracy in the above statement neither he nor the
<lb/>County of Madison guarantees the same. It is subject
<lb/>to be verified or corrected free of expense by reference
<lb/>to records in the County Treasurer's Office.
<lb/>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto
<lb/>subscribed my name and affixed my official seal at
<lb/>Wampsville, N. Y., this 5^^. day of
<lb/>June,
<lb/>TREASURER OF MADISON COUNTY
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/>
[A transcription of this page is not available.]
<pb n="3" facs="#page-002"/>
<lb/>CREDIT FINANCIAL STATEMENT AS OF. _19_ DEBIT
<lb/>Paid on signing Contract
<lb/>1 St Mortgage
<lb/>2nd Mortgage
<lb/>Int. from
<lb/>Purchase Money Mortgage ,
<lb/>Security on Lease
<lb/>Rent from..
<lb/>Taxes
<lb/>Water Rates
<lb/>Sewer Rents
<lb/>Assessments
<lb/>Total Credit
<lb/>Purchase Price
<lb/>Insurance
<lb/>T.
<lb/>Water Rates
<lb/>Sewer Rents
<lb/>Fuel
<lb/>Total Debit
<lb/>Total Credit
<lb/>Balance Paid
<lb/>Closing of title under the within contract is hereby adjourned to
<lb/>o'clock, at
<lb/>as of 19 .
<lb/>Dated, 19
<lb/>19 , at
<lb/>; title to be closed and all adjustments to be made
<lb/>For value received, the within contract and all the right, title and interest of the purchaser thereunder are hereby assigned,
<lb/>transferred and set over unto
<lb/>and said assignee hereby assumes all obligations of the purchaser thereunder.
<lb/>Dated, ,
<lb/>n. OfifGi. i ?.
<lb/>19
<lb/>Purchaser
<lb/>Assignee of Purchaser
<lb/>E-
<lb/>h
<lb/>I
<lb/>-ilLT
<lb/>c-=c-
<lb/>THE OBSERVANCE OF THE FOLLOWING SUGGESTIONS WILL SAVE TIME
<lb/>AND TROUBLE AT THE CLOSING OF THIS TITLE
<lb/>The SELLER should bring with him all insurance policies and duplicates, receipted bills for taxes, assessments and
<lb/>water rates, and any leases, deeds or agreements affecting the property.
<lb/>When there is a water meter on the premises, he should order it read, and bring bills therefor to the closing.
<lb/>If there arc mortgages on the property he should produce receipts showing to what date the interest has been P^'d,
<lb/>the principal or rate of interest has been reduced, he should produce certificates of such reduction signed and acknowledged by
<lb/>the holders of the mortgages.
<lb/>He should furnish to the purchaser a full list of tenants, giving the names, rent paid by each, and date to which the rent
<lb/>has been paid.
<lb/>The PURCHASER should be prepared with cash or a certified check drawn to his own order. The check may be
<lb/>certified for an approximate amount and cash may be provided for the balance of the settlement.
<lb/>Startdard N. Y. B.T. U. Form 8041 *2-61-50M—Contract of Sale.
<lb/>CONSULT YOUR LAWYER BEFORE SIGNING THIS INSTRUMENT-THIS INSTRUMENT SHOULD BE USED BY LAWYERS ONLY.
<lb/>THIS AGREEMENT, made the day of nineteen hundred and SiXty-OB©
<lb/>BETWEEN
<lb/>MjURIOM WHISHT MOHfGOMlRy, as Executrix of the Will of
<lb/>BOMSfk ORCILIA BMJ3WIH, deceasedi, residing at 24 Konroe Place,
<lb/>Borough of Brooklyn, City and State of Hew York,
<lb/>.v.,A _
<lb/>-I
<lb/>hereinafter described as the seller, and I • ■ '
<lb/>PHEDERICK e. KOSHER and ALICE H, KOSHER, hi# wife,
<lb/>of Earlville, Kadison County, New York, ■ Y Y
<lb/>hereinafter described as the purchase© ,
<lb/>WITNESSETH, that the seller agrees to sell and convey, and the purchaser agrees to purchase, all that certain plot, piece
<lb/>or parcel of land, with the buildings and improvements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in theTOWn of
<lb/>Hamilton, County of Kadison and State of Mew York, and lying and
<lb/>being on the west side of North Kain St, in the Village of Earlville,
<lb/>Kadison Co., Mew York, aad-bo«wid©d'-«ad--4@eer^sb©#'«««-fo3.iow«^
<lb/>jofsHEbarM-s- w-^Jhe^ wNSdit-day- -oaliod-- layette-#fc,
<lb/>4UL 4^ dKmth-4:&gt;y^ -owned-hy- 43h«a^
<lb/>■of- f-.-r Ar hr -of- Krai- Ar.- -Carri-o9r=i5fie- -east- -by .
<lb/>4da©-her©tof-€H?©- «a4i»-/-St-.-i- -eam^
<lb/>jcxtiw©y.©d--te- 4 Broee- •OoOTiel-l-ar
<lb/>M-e- dated-■Sei)t%-•l-aV^-907-&gt;--apeeorded--in-Ifedi-eon--Oo-,
<lb/>Xa,©rtC^©---0«Hl"Ce-Bept-i---e^,--I-907,. premises to be conveyed hereunder ^
<lb/>being house and lot occupied by Aletta Orcelia Baldwin as her resi
<lb/>dence at the time of her death.
<lb/>Said premises also known as 45 Morth Kain Street, Earlville, Kadison
<lb/>County, Mew York.
<lb/>■  '.i
<lb/>This sale includes all right, title and interest, if any, of the seller in and to any land lying in the bed of any street, road or
<lb/>avenue opened or proposed, in front of or adjoining said premises, to-the center line thereof, and all right, title and interest
<lb/>of the seller in and to any award made or to be made in lieu thereof and in and to any unpaid award for damage to said
<lb/>premises by reason of change of grade of any street; and the seller will execute and deliver to the purchaser, on closing of
<lb/>title, or thereafter, on demand, all proper instruments for the conveyance of such title aiid the "assi^meht and "collection of
<lb/>any such award.
<pb n="4" facs="#page-003"/>
<lb/>The price is I^IIH THOUSAMD AMD FIVE HWRED (|9,500.00)
<lb/>Dollars, payable as follows:
<lb/>OHE THOUSAND (|l,000.00) "Dollars,
<lb/>on the signing of this contract, by check subject to collection, the receipt of which is hereby acknowledged;
<lb/>EIQHT THOUSAND AND FIVE HDNDRID ($8,500.00) Dollars,
<lb/>in cash or good certified check on the delivery of the deed as hereinafter provided;
<lb/>sdMboK
<lb/>" :8::IS!Oigdus!Q£#!igde^:3m:tx»xicko3id£9jSQsdeJS»9te^
<lb/>sdjcxxbcxxgixgucKi^ogQj^sssckxxiissxxAiRj^xxxiiua^scERXbscKHsi^BKiitx^
<lb/>Xgdkael)0l^teXXjil!dk!O!9btk3@d!tnXXXXXXXXXXXXKK3S2{9CXQi2^XXXXXX^UC!CXXXXXXXXXtXXeKKl^^
<lb/>:;dxRK&amp;@sgb[!!caoxxoe!ts»i!^3^cxxiidMac9dass3q0exxxkigdKgas}dx3«Q^
<lb/>x«3ffi«!)gx3dmofaacxabdx6ejadittKAKki!aiexxaxsKdiac«i^^^
<lb/>3dxKi6dmdo!SBd;xg!«ai6dk«SQic5bdicxscBEA3d3B!mB»KxkisM5dBi*x$dH3aBHko^
<lb/>skximxkeds^xgi^xssKXK^iQ^xgiodii^affiidxscxQi^
<lb/>xllscmxXEKgclitijxxssgtxiXBSSXXgixdsxxxQ^M^racKs^^
<lb/>Said premises are sold and are to be conveyed subject tb:
<lb/>I. Zoning regulations and ordinances of the city, town or village in which the premises lie which are not violated by
<lb/>existing structures. . i
<lb/>Consents by the seller or any former o'wner of premises, for the erection of any structure or structures on, under
<lb/>or .above any street or streets on which said premises may abut.
<lb/>_3. Encroachments of stoops, areas, cellar steps, trim and cornices, jf any, upon any street or highway.
<lb/>H ■
<lb/>:; •rjiizoAeoK-fSp fjw.icou nc,' 9!^q pi".Tc? jg ('pc.;,.
<lb/>3 2Cj| Jfua i;iiLiACA' r|K bi,ac|iBSGt t'SUtir !:: brtrcp~:'r.* •
<lb/>5^
<lb/>If there be a mortgage on the premises the seller agrees to deliver to the purchaser at the time of delivery of the deed a proper
<lb/>certificate executed and acknowledged by the holder of such mortgage and in form for recording, certifying as to the amount
<lb/>of the unpaid principal and interest ther.eon, date of maturity thereof and rate of interest thereon, and the seller shall pay the
<lb/>fees for recording such certificate.
<lb/>All notes or notices of violations of law or municipal ordinances, orders or requirements noted in or issued by the Depart
<lb/>ments of Housing and Buildings, Fire, Labor, Health, or other State or Municipal Department having jurisdiction against
<lb/>or affecting the premises at the date hereof, shall be complied with by the seller and the premises shall be conveyed free of
<lb/>the same, and this provision of this contract shall survive delivery of the deed hereunder. The seller shall furnish the purchaser
<lb/>with an authorization to make the necessary searches therefor.
<lb/>If, at the time of the delivery of the deed, the premises or any part thereof shall be or shall have been affected by an assess
<lb/>ment or assessments which are or may become payable in annual installments, of which the first installment is then a charge
<lb/>or lien, or has been paid, then for the purposes of this contract all the unpaid installments of any such assessment, including
<lb/>those which are to become due and payable after the delivery of the deed, shall be deemed to be due and payable and
<lb/>to be liens upon the premises affected thereby and shall be paid and discharged by the seller, upon the delivery of the deed.
<lb/>The following are to be apportioned:
<lb/>_ [3) Premiums on existing transferable insurance policies
<lb/>or renewals of those expiring prior to the cIosing.~X'^) Taxes and sewer rents, if any, on the basis of the fiscal year for
<lb/>which assessed. (5) Water charges on the basis of the calendar year. (6) Fuel, if any.
<lb/>If the closing of the title shall occur before the tax rate is fixed, the apportionment of taxes shall be upon the basis of the
<lb/>tax rate for the next preceding year applied to the latest assessed valuation.
<lb/>If there be a water meter on the premises, the seller shall furnish a reading to date not more than thirty days prior to the time
<lb/>herein set for closing title, and the unfixed meter charge and the unfixed sewer rent, if any, beised thereon for the intervening
<lb/>time shall be apportioned on the basis of such last reading.
<lb/>The deed shall be the usual Bargain EJid Sal© With Covenants against Qrantor'a Acts
<lb/>deed in proper statutory short form for record and shall be duly executed, acknowledged, and have revenue stamps in the
<lb/>proper amount affixed thereto by the seller, at the seller's expense, so as to convey to the purchaser the fee simple of the said
<lb/>premises, free of all encumbrances, except as herein stated, and shall also contain the covenant required by subdivision 5 of
<lb/>Section 13 of the Lien Law.
<lb/>xsidicx^iSKxxsdbciiHsxx
<lb/>lig^eT to pay and discharge,
<lb/>with the interest and penalties thereon to a date not less than two business days after the date of closing title, may at the
<lb/>option of the seller be allowed to the purchaser out of the balance of the purchase price, provided official bills therefor with
<lb/>interest and penalties thereon figured to said date are furnished by the seller at the closing. If at the date of closing title there may
<lb/>be any other liens or encumbrances which the seller is obligated to pay and discharge, the seller may use any portion of the
<lb/>balance of the purchase price to satisfy the same, provided the seller shall have delivered to the purchaser at the closing of title
<lb/>instruments in recordable form and sufficient to satisfy such liens and encumbrances of record, together with the cost of recording
<lb/>or filing said instruments. The purchaser, if request is inade within a reasonable time prior to the date of closing of title, agrees
<lb/>to provide at the closing separate certified checks as requested, aggregating the amount of the balance of the purchase price, to
<lb/>facilitate the satisfaction of any such liens or encumbrances. The existence of any such taxes or other liens and eticumbrances
<lb/>shall not be deemed objections to title if the seller shall comply with the foregoing requirements.
<lb/>If a search of the title discloses judgments, bankruptcies or other returns against other persons having names the same as or
<lb/>similar to that of the seller, the seller will on request deliver to the purchaser an affidavit showing that such judgments, bank
<lb/>ruptcies or other returns are not against the seller.
<lb/>In the event that the seller is unable to convey title in accordance with the terms of this contract, the sole liability of the seller
<lb/>will be to refund to the purchaser the amount paid on account of the purchase price and to pay the net cost of examining the
<lb/>title, which cost is not to exceed the charges fixed by the New York Board of Title Underwriters, and the net cost of any
<lb/>survey made in connection therewith incurred by the purchaser, and upon such refund and payment being made this contract
<lb/>shall be considered canceled.
<lb/>The deed shall be delivered upon the receipt of said payments at the office of T * B » Lull » lOGAtQdi At
<lb/> ed HEM
<lb/>All sums paid on account of this contract, and the reasonable expenses of the examination of the title to said premises and
<lb/>of the survey, if any, made in connection therewith are hereby made hens thereon, but such hens shall not continue after
<lb/>default by the purchaser under this contract.
<lb/>All fixtures and articles of personal property attached or appurtenant to or used in connection with said premises are repre
<lb/>sented to be owned by the seller, free from all liens and encumbrances except as herein stated, and are included in this sale;
<lb/>without limiting the generality of the foregoing, such fixtures and articles of personal property include plumbing, heating,
<lb/>lighting and cooking fixtures, air conditioning fixtures and units, ranges, refrigerators, radio and television aerials, bathroom
<lb/>and kitchen cabinets, mantels, door mirrors, Venetian blinds, shades, screens, awnings, storm windows, window boxes, storm
<lb/>doors, mail boxes, weather vanes, flagpoles, pumps, shrubbery and outdoor statuary. if included, in
<lb/>the sale all household goods as per list dated May 15, 1961# except 1
<lb/>©irlville. New Yorkato'clock on July IStj19 61.
<lb/>The parties agree that Frederick BaUSr
<lb/>brought about this sale and the seller agrees to pay the commissiol^ at the rates established or adopted by the Board of Real
<lb/>Estate Brokers in the locality where the property is situated.
<lb/>It is understood and agreed that all understandings and agreements heretofore had between the parties hereto are merged in this
<lb/>contract, which alone fully and completely expresses their agreement, and that the same is entered into after full investigation,
<lb/>neither party relying upon any statement or representation, not embodied in this contract, made by the other. The purchaser has
<lb/>inspected the buildings standing on said premises and is thoroughly acquainted with their condition.
<lb/>This agreement may not be changed or terminated orally. The stipulations aforesaid are to apply to and bind the heirs,
<lb/>executors, administrators, successors and assigns of the respective parties.
<lb/>if two or more persons constitute either the seller or the purchaser, the word "seller" or the word "purchaser" shall be
<lb/>construed as if it read "sellers" or "purchasers" whenever the sense of this agreement so requires.
<lb/>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, this agreement has been duly executed by the parties hereto,
<lb/>Sellers
<lb/>In pr^ence^of: ^
<lb/>'fChjf£xriK^lmir!up&gt;^ , Marion ¥plght(75o.ntgom@ry#(^/as Ixecutrls!
<lb/>of %ii@ Will of Aletta Oreelia BsLldwir
<lb/>^ deceased,
<lb/>Furehaaerss
<lb/>R.
<lb/>F^derl^ ^MoSher
<lb/>Alice W. Mosher
<lb/>NOTE: FIRE LOSSES. This form of contract contains no express provision as to risk of loss by fire or other casualty
<lb/>before delivery of the deed. Unless express provision is made, the provisions of Section 240-a of the Real Property
<lb/>Law will apply. This section also places risk of loss upon purchaser if title or possession is transferred prior to closing.
<pb n="5" facs="#page-004"/>
<lb/>William L. Burke
<lb/>Attdrney-at- Law
<lb/>Hamilton, New York
<lb/>Madisdn County Attorney
<lb/>May 5, 1967
<lb/>Mr, Fred Mosher,
<lb/>Earlville, New York
<lb/>Dear Fred:
<lb/>Enclosed is your discharge of mortgage which has been
<lb/>recorded, which you have already paid for, and I de
<lb/>sire to thank you for the same, j
<lb/>ilQ.xy truly yours, &gt;&lt;
<lb/>William L, Burke,
<lb/>wlb/h
<lb/>End,
<pb n="6" facs="#page-005"/>
[A transcription of this page is not available.]
<pb n="7" facs="#page-006"/>
<lb/>im 14i mcEtiai Denblanx registered u. s. pat. officeDENNIS LAW BLANK CO.. PUBLISHERS. BUFFALO. N. Y.
<lb/>FORM 664 N. Y. DISCHARGE OF MORTGAGE (FROM A CORPORATION)
<lb/>(Laws of 1917, Chap. 681, Statutory Form L L)
<lb/>^.mW eU M\m % iktm
<lb/>That The Oneida Val ley National Bank of Oneida, New York
<lb/>does hereby certify that a certain indenture of mortiage, hearing date the
<lb/>25th day o/January Mneteen Hundred and Sixty-Two
<lb/>made and executed by
<lb/>FREDERICK C. MOSHER and ALICE MOSHER
<lb/>to secure payment of the principal sum of
<lb/>- - - - SIX THOUSAND and - - -00/100 - Dollars,
<lb/>and interest, and duly recorded in the office of County Clerk of the
<lb/>County of Madison , -T". Y., in Liber 349 of mortgages,
<lb/>page 557 , on the 29th day of January Nineteen
<lb/>Hundred and Sixty-Two , which mortgage has not been ̂ assigned,
<lb/>is paid, and does hereby consent that the same be discharged of record.
<lb/>^fn ot The party of
<lb/>the first part has caused its corporate seal to be
<lb/>hereunto affixed, and these presents to be signed
<lb/>by its duly authorized officer this 1 8th
<lb/>day of Apr i 1 Xineteen Hundred
<lb/>and Sixty-Seven
<lb/>ONEIDA VALLEY NATlONA^i BANK OF ONEIDA
<lb/>aniel M. Warne,
<lb/>Y(kK ..T
<lb/>Pres i dent
<lb/>O) . If the mortgage has not ̂ en otsigh^d, the certificate shall so state. If the mortgage has been assigned, in whole or in part, strike oui the words "has not.
<lb/>been" and insert "was,-"' and set forth the date of each ossignment in the chain of title of the person or persons signing the certificate, the names of the assignor
<lb/>and assignee, the interest assigned, and, if the assignment has been recorded, the book and page where it has been recorded, or the serial number of such record;
<lb/>or if the assignment is beina recorded simultaneously with the certificate of discharge, the certificate shall so state. Reel Property Law, §321, Subc.
<pb n="8" facs="#page-007"/>
<lb/>of ̂tw ̂Jork
<lb/>(Coiittty of Mad i son
<lb/>of
<lb/>00.1
<lb/>On this l8th d&lt;^y of
<lb/>Sixty-Seven before me personally came
<lb/>Apr I 1 M'ineteen Hundred and
<lb/>Daniel M. Warne
<lb/>to me personally known who, being by me duly sworn did depose and say
<lb/>that he resides in Hamilton, New York
<lb/>that he is the\\c&amp; Presidento/ The Oneida Valley National Bank of Oneic
<lb/>the corporation described in and which executed the above Instrument; that he
<lb/>knows the seal of said corporation; that the seal affixed to said Instrument is
<lb/>such corporate seal; that it was so affixed by order of the Board of Directors
<lb/>of said corporation, and that he signed his name thereto by like order.
<lb/>fmpiwftf
<lb/>Adelaide c. peckham
<lb/>Notary Public, Sir; ' YotH
<lb/>Appointed in N.y. .,, 'ounly / yj
<lb/>My rnmmisiian axpitoj 3Q^ jp u j
<lb/>&lt;CGOq;oLUo
<lb/>aeLU Q
<lb/>oLU
<lb/>IE
<lb/>_J —
<lb/>o73O&gt; O
<lb/>Cs:en:LUtoLU
<lb/>&lt;C Li.
<lb/>Q OQLUOLU
<lb/>ae—12
<lb/>Ll.&lt;cO
<lb/>z -
<lb/>.0 olHf
<lb/>LU
<lb/>J S g
<lb/>141
<pb n="9" facs="#page-008"/>
<lb/>FORM 508 LW N. Y. CONTRACT PROPERTY TUTBLANX registered u. s. pat. offic
<lb/>TUTTI-E LAW PRINT. PUBUSHERS. RUTLAND, VT. OS?'
<lb/>Made this 14 th day of Nov&amp;mber in the year
<lb/>Mneteen Hundred and Seventy-two,
<lb/>^^^ttlt^^ltFREDERICK C. MOSHER, of 45 N. Main Street, Village of
<lb/>Earlville, County of Madison, State of New York,
<lb/>party of the first part, and
<lb/>RICHARD L. ALGER, of Sherburne (no street address).
<lb/>County of Chenango, State of New York, party
<lb/>of the second part, in the manner following:—The said parties have and hereby do
<lb/>mutually covenant and agree as follows: The par^ of the first part to sell, and
<lb/>the part y of the second part to purchase AU tljat nr )larrel of Canb
<lb/>sit Cuate in the
<lb/>of Madison
<lb/>Village of Earlvi1le ounty
<lb/>and State of Jfew York, briefly described as follows:
<lb/>a house and lot located at 45 N, Main Street in the Village of Earl
<lb/>villeand Town of Hamilton, County of Madison, State of New York,
<lb/>for the sum of fen thousand, five hundred ($10,500,00) dollars
<lb/>which sum the said party of the second part hereby agree^ to pay to the party
<lb/>of the first part, as follows:
<lb/>Two thousand ($2,000,00) dollars down and the balance of eight
<lb/>thousand, five hundred ($8,500,00) dollars on the closing
<lb/>which is to take place in the office of William L, Burke at
<lb/>his office at 29 Lebanon Street, Village of Hamilton, on or
<lb/>about the 15th day of December, 1972,
<lb/>It is understood and agreed between the parties hereto that
<lb/>the within transaction is predicated upon the purchaser being
<lb/>able to obtain financing from a duly licensed lending
<lb/>institution.
<lb/>In the event that the purchaser is unable to obtain financing,
<lb/>then in that event, the seller agrees to return to the purchaser
<lb/>that portion of the pxirchase price and the status of the parties
<lb/>shall be the same as if the within contract had never been
<lb/>entered into.
<lb/>Said. 4iart of JJi&amp;. .second ..pnrl'.QisQ jogrec &gt; io..p.cLy. JLLL. fCanes jmd Assessments
<lb/>which .shalL heJnxed. oz ..assessed, upon. said, piewises. fiom
<lb/>taxes shall be pro-rated as of the date of the closing.
<pb n="10" facs="#page-009"/>
<lb/>And the said part y of the first part, on receiving such payment
<lb/>at the time and in the manner
<lb/>above mentioned, shall, at his ovm proper cost and expense, execute
<lb/>and deliver to the said part y of the second part, or to his assigns, a
<lb/>Warranty deed, forty year abstract of title, current tax
<lb/>receipts, ten year tax search, Villap.e tax search.
<lb/>It is agreed that the part y of the second part shall have possession of
<lb/>said premises from and after the closincr.
<lb/>Aw&amp; it y sgrwis that the stipulations aforesaid are to apply to and
<lb/>birvd the heirs, executors, administrators and assigns of the respective parties.
<lb/>seals the day and year first above written.
<lb/>The parties have hereunto set hands and
<lb/>3ln xrf
<lb/>Frederick C. Mosher
<lb/>Richard L. Alger
<lb/>%
<lb/>m
<lb/>88.:
<lb/>ison
<lb/>Village Earlville j
<lb/>On this 14th day of November H^ineteen Hundred and
<lb/>Seventy-two before me, the subscriber, personally appeared
<lb/>FREDERICK C. MOSHER
<lb/>to me personally known and known to me to be the same person described
<lb/>in and who executed the within Instrument, and he duly
<lb/>acknowledged to me that he executedjthe same
<lb/>7. STATE OF NEW YORK ) _
<lb/>COUNTY OF CHENANGO) / I'u, .Notary Rfiblic
<lb/>VILLAGE ) ss.: On tM^Z/ day o1972,
<lb/>before me, the subscriber, peT(gx&gt;nany appeared
<lb/>RICHARD L. ALGER
<lb/>to me personally known and known tojne to be the same person
<lb/>described in and who executed the iptljiin Instrument and he duly
<lb/>acknowledged to me that he executecKthe same.
<lb/>^ Iccu-r*COos:ucccaQcuDCU.0Ha:LUCJ3nJQq:&lt;XuocCvJa:)2
<lb/>7^- /Not^y Public
<lb/>lU
<lb/>D ̂ I m i 5
<lb/>I i u
<lb/>J ■r z u -
<lb/>■5 Z z
<lb/>^ d; p
<lb/>&lt; P
<lb/>J h S
<lb/>=1 ' I
<pb n="11" facs="#page-010"/>
<lb/>AGREEMENT
<lb/>WHEREAS, FREDERICK C. MOSHER, of 45 N. Main Street,
<lb/>Village of Earlville, Town of Hamilton, County of Madison,
<lb/>State of New York and RICHARD L, ALGER, of Sherburne (no
<lb/>street address). County of Chenango, State of New York, have
<lb/>entered into an agreement for the purchase of property owned
<lb/>by Frederick C, Mosher situate at 45 N, Main Street, in the
<lb/>Village of Earlville, Town of Hamilton, County of Madison,
<lb/>State of New York, and
<lb/>WHEREAS, Frederick C. Mosher, the seller, is an
<lb/>antif i! j dealer who has acquired many items of personal property
<lb/>for tia purposes of resale, which are currently stored in his
<lb/>house at 45 N, Main Street in the Village of Earlville, and
<lb/>WHEREAS, Richard L, Alger has no place to live, it
<lb/>is mutually covenanted and agreed that Frederick C. Mosher
<lb/>shall have until March 1, 1973 to clear the items of personal
<lb/>property hereinabove referred to, and it is further
<lb/>AGREED, that Frederick C. Mosher agrees to rent a
<lb/>room at a nominal rent to the purchaser, Richard L, Alger,
<lb/>until the closing, and it is further
<lb/>AGREED, that Richard L, Alger shall be allowed to
<lb/>tear down the barn curr&gt;.ntly standing on the property for
<lb/>salvage value, however, it is further
<lb/>AGREED, that all the contents of the barn are
<lb/>property belonging to the seller, Frederick C. Mosher.
<pb n="12" facs="#page-011"/>
<lb/>T M H V 3 .1 n n A
<lb/>nifiM .M 3o .3 :«3Tfl3Cs3fi3 ,aA3f}3HW
<lb/>,no8ibi^ 3o yJnuoD .nolIxmsH 3o rrwoT .slliviiBa 3o agBinV
<lb/>on) 9fiTud*rari3 3o ,^a3JA ,J G?iAH3Ta bns ;ItoY waM lt&gt; 31bJ2
<lb/>©VBfi , MtoY wsM 3o sJgJH jO^ifrBnadD 3o vjnuoD .(aesibba JsaiJe
<lb/>bsnwo y^TSffoiq to ssBdaTuq aril to^ Xnamaetge ns oJni; bsTsJaii-
<lb/>arfj ni jJasTdP nif&gt;M ,H gA Jb a^sijjfe larizoM ,3 /}Di-xabaT3 yd
<lb/>,fi08fbsM 3o ylnuoD ,noJlxfrrBH lo nwoT ,aIliviTB3 3o agsIIiV
<lb/>bnfi ,){foY waK 3o a3BJ8
<lb/>fiB ai .tallaz add .teriaoM .3 jfoiTebaTa ,aA3«3HW
<lb/>yJtaqoirq lBfTo?T©q 3o emaJi ynam ba-riupDB aari oriw lolnah I 'iJnB
<lb/>eld rri bsioJe ylJna-ntuD ©tb rioiriw ,alB897 lo gaeoqioq f .J
<lb/>fans ,allivli£a 3o agBHiV aril ni tasrtP nisH .H gA Ib aauori
<lb/>,9vil o.t aDJBlq on end Ta«iA .J bTsdoiJ! ,RA3JI3nw
<lb/>-rarizoM .3 jfoitabaTa i&amp;dl basT^B bne balnsnavoo yllBulom ai
<lb/>isnoejQq Jo amaJi adJ tssIo oJ £561 ,I rioii^ I iJnu avBri IIaria
<lb/>lariliul ai Jx bne ,oJ b9-na3ai avodBrrxaiari yJiaqotq
<lb/>•• ,-f9!»IA »J bTBfiDxIi , raaBxioTijq aril oJ Inai iBnxmon b Ib mooi
<lb/>'X9rilTu3 ex tx bfiE ,gnxeoIo aril Ixinu
<lb/>ol bswol Ib ad llBJe isgIA .J biBrioxd IbHI ,033If3A
<lb/>to3 yliaqoTq aril no gnibnBla ylln.iTUD nisd aril nwob tBdl
<lb/>-xariiTu3 ax ix ,7avawori ,9uIbv agBVlsa
<lb/>aiB HTBd aril 3o alnalnoo aril 11b iBril .QdaPDA
<lb/>.larieoM ,3 jJoxiabaid ,i9ilae aril ol gnxgnolad yliaqoiq
<lb/>f.?,
<lb/>[.3,
<lb/>Jl
<lb/>T
<lb/>ij A:
<lb/>jVXV
<lb/>hbjumJIIUA
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
