<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>harrison george elmer documents</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-002" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-002.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-003" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-003.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-004" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-004.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-005" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-005.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-006" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-006.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-007" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-007.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-008" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-008.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-009" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-009.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-010" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-010.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-011" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-011.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-012" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-012.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-013" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_george_elmer_documents/p-013.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>0
<lb/>t
<lb/>n-n
<lb/>Ol^rttfg
<lb/>as appears
<lb/>mmMmm1^ I
<lb/>^ nffirialtag, in iij
<lb/>^ front lij:e^.&lt;i^3arrtage ^rp;feter of tipOy^iptrrij.
<lb/>|p //^'' V /X /
<lb/>^ pafei
<lb/>1  i' /vm
<lb/>immkpmmmm
<lb/>^  ̂ ^corbtng io l^o ̂ tle of fijo ̂ ntan 01atl|oltc diptrcl]: ^
<lb/>ki ^ ^
<lb/>mi . . . / u - , « . .^  a^ in EOttforntitn 6nilr Ibe mias ninths ^ate of ^IMIW. JMs^ s
<lb/>^asiar
<lb/>NO. 312yF, J. REMEY CO. INC. N.Y
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/>
<lb/>•  «• — . ,Jt.l*€t/^ V, „
<lb/>cept and agree to be governed by all the
<lb/>conditions of this contract.
<lb/>Form L- P. 8
<lb/>(Use pen and mk,) Original Purchaser
<lb/>Witness:
<pb n="3" facs="#page-002"/>
<lb/>INCORPORATED.
<lb/>Paid Up Capital, $100,000
<lb/>Improved Copper LiglitniBg Conductors-
<lb/>Weather Vanes and Fixtures.
<lb/>"mi Patentceo and Manufacturers of the Only
<lb/>COPPER AUTOMATIC WATER RECEIVER
<lb/>FOR PERFECT GROUND CONNECTION.
<lb/>THIS CERTIFICATE OF AUTHORITY IS GOOD FOR SIX MONTHS FROM DATE
<lb/>Burlington, Wis., J A N 1 1920
<lb/>TO WHOM IT MAY CONCEim: . . , , j a-
<lb/>Reposing speci§ltrust and confidence in the honor and discretion oi
<lb/>cornxnission
<lb/>true and lawful agent , With full authority only In sell ouiWCopper Lightning
<lb/>' * " Conductors and Patented Water Supp-.y for the ground,
<lb/>to issue therewith our guarantee in accordance with the
<lb/>rules and regulations therein set forth, and to receive
<lb/>pay and receipt for all rods sold during the
<lb/>life of this certificate.
<lb/>THE SECURITY LIGHTNING ROD CO.
<lb/>President.
<lb/>Attest:
<lb/>Ql;
<lb/>Secretary.
<pb n="4" facs="#page-003"/>
<lb/>yk-A^SI
<lb/>sn/
<lb/>1
<lb/>SrifM
<lb/>&lt;L^\QiH.Vf5«
<pb n="5" facs="#page-004"/>
<lb/>f' ^.
<lb/>A
<lb/>-A »
<pb n="6" facs="#page-005"/>
<lb/>/V
<lb/>GENERAL EXCHANGE INSURANCE CORPORATION
<lb/>Standard
<lb/>Automobile Policy
<lb/>FORM
<lb/>NEW YORK. NEW YORK
<lb/>(HEREINAFTER CALLED THE COMPANY)
<lb/>COMPANY
<lb/>In consideration of the stipulations herein named and of the premiums hereinafter specifically mentioned, does insure
<lb/>the dealer and the purchaser named below, and the General Motors Acceptance Corporation as their interests may appear,
<lb/>and their legal representatives (hereinafter called the Assured) TO AN AMOUNT NOT EXCEEDING THE ACTUAL
<lb/>CASH VALUE OF THE PROPERTY AT THE TIME ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE OCCURS, nor, in any event, the
<lb/>Limits of Liability herein specified, against direct loss or damage from the perils specifically insured against herein and
<lb/>designated by a premium, to the automobile herein described and the equipment usually attached thereto, while within the
<lb/>territorial limits of the states comprising the United States, the District of Columbia, Alaska and the Dominion of Canada,
<lb/>including while on coastwise steamer between ports within said limits. The term of this insurance commences at noon on the
<lb/>effective date named herein and terminates at noon on the expiration date named herein.
<lb/>Acknowledgment is hereby made of the notice of the existence of a lien on the herein described automobile, in favor of
<lb/>said Dealer or General Motors Acceptance Corporation or their assignees.
<lb/>The description of the automobile insured herein and the facts respecting its purchase are as follows:
<lb/>Purchased
<lb/>New or Used
<lb/>YEAR &amp; MODEL
<lb/>MAKE
<lb/>!IVade N^c
<lb/>K Truck, Tonnage
<lb/>BODY TYPE
<lb/>MOTOR
<lb/>NUMBER
<lb/>MFG'8
<lb/>SERIAL No.
<lb/>LIST
<lb/>PRICE
<lb/>CASH SELLING
<lb/>PRICE
<lb/>Used 1931 Chev. Coupe 2781375 AE56580 $535. $215.
<lb/>Dealer.. Purcell Motor
<lb/>The automobile described is and will be used as follows:
<lb/>The Purchaser's occupation is...£?t.r£.®.5.^X.
<lb/>POLICY NUMBER: Bn....5aQ.Jl
<lb/>(Refer to this number in all correspondence) i||
<lb/>PERILS INSURED AGAINST
<lb/>(see Definitions on Page 2)
<lb/>ONLY those perils for which a specific
<lb/>premium is shown are covered.
<lb/>(a)(b)(c)(d)(e)
<lb/>Fire, Lightning and Transportation...
<lb/>Theft, Robbery and Pilferage .ITheft Form
<lb/>Specify "Broad"» or "$ ... Deductible"
<lb/>Tornado and Flood...
<lb/>Additional Coverage (Including Tornado and Flood)..
<lb/>Accidental Collision or Upset $...-5Q..«jQ.Q. Deductible
<lb/>TERM
<lb/>Effective Date Expiration Date
<lb/>May 18, I937 toMay 18, 1938
<lb/>Premium Limits of Liability
<lb/>.12
<lb/>Actual Value
<lb/>not to exceed
<lb/>$175.00
<lb/>Actual Value Less
<lb/>Collision Deductible Provided
<lb/>Purchaser , Elmer Harrison
<lb/>Street RD #1
<lb/>City and State Beaver Dams, New York steuben Township
<lb/>'^-1 y
<lb/>This policy shall not be valid unless countersigned by the duly aut^or^^ agent the" 'Company
<lb/>at Bf'lo. R.Y. - j-/-- ^ —Agent
<lb/>^ Ttiii policy is subject fo tho CONDITIONS pointed on revarso
<lb/>GEIC 1001 New 3SM—7-13-36
<pb n="7" facs="#page-006"/>
<lb/>lOlS 9VWD
<lb/>RETURN WITHIN S DAYS TO
<lb/>General Motors
<lb/>Acceptance Corporation ! ^
<lb/>1100 MAIN STREET, . - ?
<lb/>ijispt??!
<lb/>k  -iLpL
<lb/>PA I p
<lb/>^j| METER 5 52Ei3
<lb/>J
<pb n="8" facs="#page-007"/>
<lb/>General Motors Acceptance Corporation
<lb/>1100 Main Street
<lb/>Buffalo, N. Y.
<lb/>May 26, 1938
<lb/>iir, Elmer Harrison
<lb/>RD 1
<lb/>Bsa-rer Dams, Y.
<lb/>Dear Sir: 50031 - P16
<lb/>In acknowledging receipt of the final payment on your
<lb/>account, for which we thank you, may we express our
<lb/>appreciation for the opportunity we have had in serving
<lb/>you. We are returning your contract to the dealer
<lb/>from whom you made your purchase for delivery to you.
<lb/>Over eleven million buyers have taken advantage of the
<lb/>low cost General Motors Instalment Plan through dealers
<lb/>in General Motors products. This plan includes terms
<lb/>to fit the buyer's needs, valuable insurance protec
<lb/>tion on cars and trucks, and a friendly, helpful
<lb/>relationship.
<lb/>To the prospective buyer of household equipment or of
<lb/>personal and business transportation. General Motors
<lb/>offers a wide range of products, whose quality has been
<lb/>demonstrated by widespread public preference. Perhaps
<lb/>at this time you are considering the purchase of one
<lb/>of the products listed on the following page. If so,
<lb/>the advantages of the General Motors Instalment Plan
<lb/>are again available to you.
<lb/>Should you desire to use G?JIAC as a reference, we will
<lb/>be glad to answer any inquiries that may be received.
<lb/>Yp^urs very t
<lb/>Branch Manager.
<pb n="9" facs="#page-008"/>
<lb/>FEDERAL SECURITY AGENCY
<lb/>SOCIAL SECURITY BOARD
<lb/>Bureau of Old-Age and 155 St. ,
<lb/>Survivors Insurance ^^ev: York 17»
<lb/>Area Office
<lb/>CERTIFICATE OF AWARD
<lb/>Field Office; Syracuse, N.Y.
<lb/>l^re, Mary Ann Harrison,
<lb/>Spring St.,
<lb/>Hamilton, H.Y. Date: July 6, 19'i3
<lb/>Claim Number: 07^05-7^92^
<lb/>l^ear Mgdam: W, E, George H,, Harrison
<lb/>This is to certify that you are entitled to Widow's Insurance Benefits,
<lb/>payable monthly.
<lb/>Your regular monthly benefit will be $ 13.35
<lb/>You became entitled to benefits as of April 19^3
<lb/>The first check includes benefits for April - Jtme I9U3 incltisive.
<lb/>The first payment is in the amount of $ 33,06*
<lb/>A check for this amount will be mailed within a fev; days.
<lb/>•Oar records show that you were entitled to a benefit of yS.90 as wife of
<lb/>George H, Harrison for March I9U3. Aleo that your husband was entitled
<lb/>to a benefit of $17.80 for Mprch I9U3. However, we are deducting these
<lb/>benefits from a lump-sum payment of $33.69 previously paid to your husband,
<lb/>The balance, or $6,99, is deducted from your widow's benefits.
<lb/>w 0. C. Pogge,
<lb/>Director.
<lb/>SEE THE REVERSE SIDE OF THIS CERTIFICATE FOR THE CONDITIONS UNDER WHICH
<lb/>THESE BENEFITS ARE NOT PAYABLE, AND FOR OTHER IMPORTANT INFORMATION.
<lb/>ALWAYS GIVE CLAIM NUMBER WHEN WRITING ABOUT YOUR CLAIM
<pb n="10" facs="#page-009"/>
<lb/>Form OA-3
<lb/>(7-42)
<lb/>CONDITIONS UNDER WHICH THESE BENEFITS ARE NOT PAYABLE
<lb/>This insurance benefit is not payable for any month in which you work for wages of
<lb/>i  _more than $14.99 in employment that is covered by the Social Security Act. This does
<lb/>not mean that because you are entitled to monthly benefits you may not work, but simply
<lb/>that for those months when you do work and earn more than $14.99 you will not be eligible
<lb/>to receive a benefit payment.
<lb/>Your entitlement to widow's insurance benefits ends with the month preceding the
<lb/>month in which you marry again. '
<lb/>Notice of the occurrence of either of the above events must be sent to the Social
<lb/>&amp;curity Board promptly, or certain penalties as provided by the Social Security Act may be
<lb/>imposed. A postal card which may be used to notify the Social Security Board was given
<lb/>to you when you filed your claim.
<lb/>If you receive an insurance benefit check for any month in which either of the above
<lb/>events occurs, you should return the check to the—
<lb/>Treasury Department, Division of Disbursement
<lb/>Located in the city shown on the face of your che(^
<lb/>-  CHANGE OF ADDRESS
<lb/>Notify the Social Security Board and your local post office immediately of any change
<lb/>of address so that your monthly insurance benefit checks will not be delayed. A postal card
<lb/>which may be used to notify the Social Security Board was given to you when you filed your
<lb/>claim.
<lb/>RECONSIDERATION OR HEARING
<lb/>A claimant for old-age 'and surviyors insurance benefits has a right to a reconsidera
<lb/>tion or hearing if he is not satisfied with the decision on his claim. A reqpest for a recon-
<lb/>_si(Jeration or hearing should-be made^roiaptly,-ii©t later than 6 months from the date of
<lb/>this certificate, and should be made through the local field office of the Social Security Board.
<lb/>CONSULT THE FIELD OFFICE SHOWN ON THE FACE OF THIS CJERTIFICATE. OR ANY
<lb/>OTHER FIELD OFFICE OF THE SOCIAL SECURITY BOARD, IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS
<lb/>CONCERNING YOUR CLAIM. HUJiiSilUNS
<lb/>ALWAYS GIVE CLAIM NUMBER WHEN WRITING ABOUT YOUR CT.ATM
<pb n="11" facs="#page-010"/>
<lb/>GUTHRIE CLINIC
<lb/>ROBERT PACKER HOSPITAL
<lb/>SAYRE, PENNSYLVANIA
<lb/>SECTION OF INTERNAL MEDICINE
<lb/>DR.S. D.CONKLIN
<lb/>DR.W. D. LANGLEY
<lb/>To Whom It May Concern:
<lb/>September 12, 1954)-
<lb/>Eq: Blmer Ijfeirrison
<lb/>At autopsy a large ttinor was removed from the left lung.
<lb/>The tumor had collapsed the major portion of the left lung and was markedly
<lb/>adherent to the great vessels of the mediastinum, especially the aorta. Only
<lb/>the tumor was removed and a pathological section was made. Tlie pathological
<lb/>report showed this tumor to he a neurofihro sarcoma, a hi^ly malignant tumor.
<lb/>KRC/M
<lb/>Z.E. Crispell
<pb n="12" facs="#page-011"/>
<lb/>To F rP.
<lb/>t  the undersigned
<lb/>^  herein called the purchaser*
<lb/>hereby offers and agrees to purchase through F, J. Bostwick, Broker,
<lb/>the authori^z^d agent of the seller, the following premises:
<lb/>for the purchase price of 0 0 0 ■ 0 ̂
<lb/>the Sim of f ̂  to be paid upon the execution
<lb/>of this offer, receipt of which is hereby acknowledged, the same to
<lb/>apply upon the purchase price — balance to be paid in cash upon
<lb/>delivery of Deed,
<lb/>Further terms and conditions of-this offer are that all taxes which
<lb/>may be liens on said premises shall be paid by the seller.
<lb/>All assessments for local improvements which are now liens or which
<lb/>may become liens prior to the date originally fixed for delivery of
<lb/>Deed hereunder shall be paid by the seller.
<lb/>The seller shall execute and deliver or cause to be delivered and
<lb/>executed to said Purchaser or his assigns, a good and sufficient
<lb/>Warranty Deed of said Premises, which Deed shall convey a good
<lb/>marketable Title thereto together with an Abstract of Title.
<lb/>The purchaser shall have possession of said Premises from and after
<lb/>delivery of Deed,
<lb/>The sale thereunder shall be closed, the final cash payments made
<lb/>and Deed and other papers herein provided for shall be delivered at
<lb/>the Office of F, J. Bostwick in the City of Corning, New York
<lb/>during the month of , or such other date as shall be
<lb/>agreed upon by the Parties hereto, the Stipulations shall bind
<lb/>and shall insure to the benefit of the heirs, executors, adminis
<lb/>trators, successors and assigns of the parties hereto.
<lb/>Dated
<lb/>(Purchaser's Signature)
<lb/>Witness " ■■
<lb/>(Acceptance)
<lb/>To - //OtA/uyh&amp;ytj
<lb/>I, herein called the seller hereby accept your offer as above
<lb/>stated and accordingly agree to sell and convey said land to you
<lb/>for the price and the terms and conditions above set forth.
<lb/>Dated j ̂ / 7y^L
<lb/>(Seller's Signature
<lb/>Witness
<pb n="13" facs="#page-012"/>
<lb/>Duplicate
<lb/>CONTRACT
<lb/>a ..Have this.. / ...day of.. ... contracted with
<lb/>CORNING GRANITE &amp; MARBLE WORKS
<lb/>RICHARD G. COOK
<lb/>With the following inscription, to wing inscription, to wit
<lb/>MAiliQM.
<lb/>mnk
<lb/>j^AnmsoM
<lb/>MH/ir ^ MAMNAM T
<lb/>/sjj^l /.ms'sl, —
<lb/>No extra lettering included in ̂ is contract .y..y j. . - j. .j. —
<lb/>Monument to face , .;....'..Location of Lot.— jC#*???:..
<lb/>(PURCHASER MUST SEE THAT THE INSCRIPTION IS CORRECT, AND P^INLY WRITTEN)
<lb/>With the right of action for trespass or damages wai\md by said
<lb/>Saidjmonument will be delivered and erected in .^..^....Cemetery located
<lb/>during the month of...«^^^y"!!V-...^5? - unless Monument is not received from
<lb/>manufacturerSTfe-ffihe to do the work or unless there is ̂ pe other imavoidi elay, and then as soon thereafter as possible, in a good
<lb/>workmanlike i^nner, for which, I, *(*'. ^- v7 y. .agree to pay CORNING GRANITE
<lb/>&amp; MARBLE WORKS, the sum of.
<lb/>■NOT^EPr.
<lb/>without any relief from valuation or appraisement laws, with interest at 6 per cent., per annum after maturity, and 10% attorney's fees.
<lb/>It is further agreed that the above described monumental work is personal property and shall not be considered as part of real estate
<lb/>■ CORNING GRANITE &amp; MARBLE WORKS, until fuUy paid for, and inupon lot where it is erected, but shall remain the property of &lt;
<lb/>case of failure to make all payments within one year after due I hereby waive all right of action I may have for trespass or damages, and
<lb/>give said CORNING GRANITE &amp; MARBLE WORKS, the right and privilege to enter upon said cemetery lot, and also hereby authorize
<lb/>the Superintendent or Sexton to Cemetery in which this monument is located to permit said CORNING GRANITE &amp; MARBLE WORKS,
<lb/>to remove said monument at their own option or convenience, and all money having been paid by me may be retained by said CORNING
<lb/>GRANITE &amp; MARBLE WORKS, for damages to said monument:
<lb/>This contract shall not in any instance be countermanded or recinded only by said CORNING GRANITE &amp; MARBLE WORKS,"
<lb/>giving notice to that effect in writing to said._.
<lb/>Foundation material furnished )
<lb/>by purchaser ) No
<lb/>(Witness;) /rResidence
<lb/>P. 0
<lb/>Signed^.
<lb/>Shippin^Point...
<lb/>Salesman L
<lb/>Be Careful to Have AU Agreements Exrfessed in Writing, as No Verbal Contracts Will Be Honored.
<pb n="14" facs="#page-013"/>
<lb/>irEXT TERM'S PRINCIPAL—Leo Harrison, seated,
<lb/>who becomes principal of Painted Post High School
<lb/>next September, checks details of office with Kenneth
<lb/>Clicquennoi, retiring principal. The latter will as
<lb/>sume similar post with Alfred-Almond High School.
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
