<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>harrison leo teacher 1935</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_leo_teacher_1935/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/recent/harrison_mclaughlin/harrison_leo_teacher_1935/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>TrTEACHER'S CONTRACTIrBETWEENISole trustee, hoard of trustees, board dyeducationlof district notown ofcounty ofparties of the first partANDJ"!'{Teacher}
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/><lb/>TEACHER'S CONTRACT
<lb/>To be executed in duplicate
<lb/>one
<lb/>oard of education}
<lb/>Slljta Asmmpttt made the^
<lb/>thousand nine hundred and.,
<lb/>[Insert sole trustee, board of trustees,
<lb/>of distri^ qp. of the town of , county
<lb/>,  of the first part, and
<lb/>, residing
<lb/>Tearner s name]
<lb/>county of . rc , party of the second part,
<lb/>jt That the said party of the second part covenants and agrees to and
<lb/>with the party of the first part to teach in the public school of said district for
<lb/>the term of....(j..J^...consec^ve wjgieks, except as hereinafter provided, commencing
<lb/>on the...^..&lt;^..day , 19.c?c^^
<lb/>Atlh the said party of the first part covenants and agrees to pay unto the said
<lb/>party of the second part in consideration of such service so to be performed the
<lb/>sum of ..a week, payable at the end of each 30 days during the term of
<lb/>such employment. It is mutually understood that 4 per cent of the amount of
<lb/>each order or warrant issued in payment of the compensation required to be paid
<lb/>hereunder shall be deducted by the party of the first part, as provided by article
<lb/>43-B of the Education Law relative to the State Teachers Retirement Fund.
<lb/>Anh the said party of the second part further covenants and agrees with said
<lb/>party of the first part that the said party of the first part may provide for a vaca
<lb/>tion or vacations of not more than....j!:?....weeks in the aggregate during the afore
<lb/>said term of employment for which no compensation shall be paid by the said party
<lb/>of the first part and which shall not count as a part of the term of service above
<lb/>referred to.
<lb/>A«h the said party of the second part hereby covenants with the said party of
<lb/>the first part that ....he is duly licensed under the Laws of the State of New York
<lb/>and the rules and regulations of the State Education Department to teach in the
<lb/>public school of said district and is fully competent to perform the services required
<lb/>under this contract. ^ . ^ _
<lb/>Jtt tutittPBa the parties to these presents have hereunto set their hands
<lb/>the day and year first above written.
<lb/>Trustees
<lb/>Teacher
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
