<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Descendants of Hugh Mosher and Rebecca Maxson Through Seven Generations</title>
                <author/>
                <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
                <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
                <date>2021</date>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Copyright © 2021, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction status="high"/>
                <normalization method="markup">
                    <p>Paragraphs are maintained, but not line beginnings. Minor errors are silently corrected.</p>
                </normalization>
                <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
                    <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
                    <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
                </punctuation>
                <quotation marks="all">
                    <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
                </quotation>
                <hyphenation eol="all">
                    <p>Hyphenated words have been joined.</p>
                </hyphenation>
                <interpretation/>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date/>
                <rs type="place"/>
            </creation>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic xml:id="page-cover" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_cover.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-i" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_i.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-iv" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_iv.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-v" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_v.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-vi" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_vi.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-vii" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_vii.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-ix" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_ix.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-x" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_x.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-xi" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_xi.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-xii" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_xii.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-1" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_1.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-2" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_2.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="page-3" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/descendants_of_hugh_mosher_1980/dhmrm_1980_3.ptif/full/640,/0/default.jpg"/>
    </facsimile>
    <text xml:lang="en-US">
        <body>
            <pb n="front cover" facs="#page-cover"/>
            <pb n="i (title)" facs="#page-i"/>
            <pb n="iv (errata and addenda" facs="#page-iv"/>
            <pb n="v (forward)" facs="#page-v"/>
            <pb n="vi (about the compilers)" facs="#page-vi"/>
            <pb n="vii (acknowledgements)" facs="#page-vii"/>
            <ab>
            <pb n="ix" facs="#page-ix"/>
                <head><lb/><hi rend="bold">Hugh Mosher's Disputed Ancestry</hi></head>

            <p>
                <lb/>Research for this history has been limited to American records, but it may be well to comment on what
                has been said by persons said to have searched English records. Their reports are rather frustrating,
                for with only one exception, sources of the information are not given, and few dates are found.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>The Mosiers are said to have been Huguenots living in northeastern France until the persecution
                culminating in the Massacre of St. Bartholomew's Day in 1572 resulted in their flight to Germany and
                England. It appears that only one family had gone to England by 1600, and it had settled in Manchester,
                where it engaged in the weaving and selling of silk. The names of Stephen and James Mosier appear in
                Manchester in 1580, and Ezekiel in 1607 (said to have died in 1640). Samuel and William were in 1614
                records.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>William made his will 20 September 1620, and it was proved in the District Probate Registry of Chester,
                Chester Consistory Court, 21 June 1621. He seems to have been a young man, for he mentioned his mother
                and had only two children, both minors: John, under 21; and Mary, under 17. He named his "brother"
                Thomas Rode and wife and siblings: Anne Ramney, John (married), Thomas, Steven, and George. He requested
                that John, Thomas, and Steven "admitt my said wief (Thomasin) to be Joint partner with them in all
                theire Tradings and Commersings...."
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>Three of the brothers are said to have had sons named Hugh, Thomas' son Hugh being the Hugh Mosier who
                sailed from England on the James 12 April 1632 for Boston. This Hugh settled in Maine not later than
                1635 and died in Casco Bay before 26 July 1666, when his eldest son James was named administrator of the
                estate and James and John Mosier were bonded.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>Stephen is said to have been the father of a Hugh who was in Salem, Massachusetts, in 1636, followed
                Roger Williams to Rhode Island, received a large grant of land from him in Westerly 4 August 1674, and
                died in Newport 1694. <hi rend="bold">Not one of these statements is supported by Rhode Island or Massachusetts records</hi>.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>A few English records in the middle-seventeenth century indicate that there were Mosiers elsewhere than
                in Manchester. On 18 January 1639 Mrs. Stephen Mosyer was
                <pb n="x" facs="#page-x"/>
                bequeathed two silver salts in a will by the
                widow of Philip Hayse of St. Patrick, Exeter (Waters, <hi rend="italic">Genealogical Gleanings in England</hi>, 1185), Mary
                Mosier died 1653/4 at St. Gregory, London (Index to Prerogative Court of Canterbury, 257, vi Folio
                95). Thomas Mosier of St. Sepulchre, London, left a will proved June 1654 (ibid., vi Folio 101). On 18
                February 1664 Susanna Mosier, 27, spinster, of St. Benet Fink, London, was licensed to marry John Ellys,
                25, bachelor, of Bromley, Co. Kent, at St. Benet Fink, St. Thomas the Apostle, or St. Anthony, "now
                called the French church in London" (Foster, <hi rend="italic">London Marriage Licences</hi>, 1521-1869, p. 450).
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>Despite this paucity of records, when in 1830 it was reported that the English government had advertised
                in the Untied States for heirs of a Sir Hugh Mosher of the British East India Company, who had amassed a
                fabulous fortune and died (when?) without issue, American and Canadian Moshers sprang into action, held
                meetings, constructed sometimes faulty lineages, donated money, and sent agents to England to claim their
                inheritance. Invariably the agents were never heard from, but nevertheless, every two or three decades
                the process was repeated.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>A surprising feature of these "lineages" is that the mother of Hugh Mosher of this book is always said
                to have been Lydia Maxson, though the father was either Hugh Mosier of Maine or Ezekiel of Rhode Island.
                Accompanying statements contain so many contradictions and errors that none of the can be taken as fact,
                but all should be studied carefully for possible truths.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>In an article on some descendants of Hugh's son John in <hi rend="italic">History of Muscatine County, Iowa</hi>, 2:505, the
                tradition is said to be that Hugh descended from a Sir Hugh. The statements that Hugh lived in Bristol,
                Rhode Island and that colonial records and Dartmouth, Massachusetts, Friends records contain his
                marriage to Lydia Maxson or Dixon are erroneous. Hugh was not a Friend, and the Dartmouth Friends
                records begin in 1698.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>It is commonly said that Hugh Mosier of Casco Bay was the father of Hugh Mosher and Lydia Maxson his
                mother, but there are no records in Maine identifying Hugh's wife, or any children other than James and
                John, and no early records of Maxsons in Maine. Hugh Mosier was of an earlier generation than Hugh
                Mosher, but their having the same Christian name could as easily suggest uncle and nephew relationship
                as father and son. Furthermore, their children and grandchildren settled in different areas of New
                England and New York until the nineteenth century.
            </p>
            <pb n="xi" facs="#page-xi"/>
            <p>
                <lb/>The tradition that Ezekiel Mosher and Lydia Maxson were parents of Hugh Mosher is found among
                descendants of his sons Nicholas and Joseph. Ezekiel's sons John, a bachelor; Daniel, with a family; and
                Hugh are said to have come to Rhode Island, followed shortly by the parents, Ezekiel soon died, and John
                and Daniel and family were massacred by Indians in 1636 (not a plausible date), leaving Hugh as sole
                heir. One account mentions a sister about whom nothing was known. Several accounts say that Ezekiel left
                an immense fortune in Manchester. Still another is that Hugh's siblings, disapproving his wife, managed
                to have Hugh's share of the fortune entailed until the youngest member of the third generation was of
                age, this causing the long delay in settlement of the estate.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>The first mention of the three brothers that has come to the attention of the compilers is in the day
                book of Christopher Mosher (1796-1866) of Albany, New York. He wrote that three Mosher brothers, Hugh,
                John, and Daniel were the ones who came to America. The next is in the biography of Jonathan Brant
                Mosher (1808-76) of Chemung county, New York, in <hi rend="italic">History of Tioga, Chemung, Tompkins and Schuyler
                Counties, New York</hi>, 340c, which says that Hugh was one of three brothers but doesn't name the other two.
                The name of Ezekiel as the father of the three brothers appears in the story of a meeting in the Palmer
                House in Chicago 12 October 1883, and reported in an undated clipping from the Monmouth, Illinois
                <hi rend="italic">Gazette</hi>. Martin Mosher (1812-1900), son of David of Aurora, New York, told the gathering there that his
                father had commissioned Millard Fillmore, also of Aurora, to seek Ezekiel's will while on a trip to
                England, that Fillmore had brought back a copy, then in the Fillmore Papers in Aurora, and that Martin
                had seen it and could produce it. Perhaps it was later turned over to a Mosher, for in 1979 the three
                repositories of Fillmore Papers in New York--the Aurora Historical Society, the Buffalo and Erie County
                Historical Society, and the State University College in Oswego--reported that the will was not in their
                collections.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>That will may have been what Ina Sizer Cassidy, descendant of Martin's great-grandfather Nicholas
                referred to in a paper she deposited in the American Institute of Genealogy in Chicago, saying that her
                grandfather John Hurd Covill had records including the advertisement in 1830 for heirs, that she knew
                where to find all the proof and all the estate, but that "these things we are compelled to keep to
                ourselves until the time is right to divulge them."
            </p>
            <pb n="xii" facs="#page-xii"/>
            <p>
                Lydia Maxson as Ezekiel's wife appears in 1891 in the compilation of the descendants of James<hi rend="sup">3</hi>
                (Nicholas<hi rend="sup">2</hi>) who settled in Nova Scotia in 1760.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>In 1926 a Mosher woman, mistaken about her own lineage, knew the story of Ezekiel and appealed to the
                chief of police in Trenton, New Jersey, to locate her aunt and cousin, who were living there. After a
                search the police succeeded in finding the two living in modest circumstances, and the <hi rend="italic">New York Times</hi> of
                2 May carried an article about the two, who had "learned today" that they were among the heirs of a
                relative Ezekiel Mosher, who had "recently" died in England leaving a fortune of $132,000,000.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>Even today there are still persons living who have contributed to the search for the fortune and who
                still hope for a share. But Hugh Moshers's "fortune" and his ancestors have both eluded his descendants.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>Other elements in the story of Ezekiel, however, are too similar to what has been said and what is known
                about Hugh to be dismissed lightly.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>If his sons John and Daniel and Daniel's family were massacred by the Indians, it was not likely that it
                was in 1636, when Hugh was only three years old, but perhaps in 1656, when Hugh, too, was grown, and
                only four years away from the first Mosher record in Rhode Island (Hugh's). The doubtful story has been
                told that two of Hugh's sons were killed in King Philip's War. Was it instead his two brothers some time
                earlier?
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>Lydia Maxson as Ezekiel's wife fits in Rhode Island records perfectly. Hugh's mother is known to have
                been living in 1677, and in 1680 Lydia and Rebecca Mosher were members of his church in Tiverton. He is
                not known to have had a daughter Lydia, and the first daughter-in-law Lydia was then about fourteen
                years in the future. In early colonial days it was common for first cousins to marry, and if Lydia
                Maxson was a sister of Richard Maxson of Portsmouth, whose widow Rebecca married John Harndell of
                Newport, here were two marriages of first cousins: Lydia's daughter Mary and son Hugh to Richard's son
                John and Rebecca.
            </p>
            <p>
                <lb/>The record may yet be found that reveals Hugh's parentage.
            </p>
            </ab>
            <pb n="1" facs="#page-1"/>
            <pb n="2" facs="#page-2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="#page-3"/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
