<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Goodwife Maxson Harndell</title>
                <author/>
                <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
                <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
                <date>2021</date>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Copyright © 2021, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <correction status="high">
                    <p>Transcriptions are double-checked.</p>
                </correction>
                <normalization method="markup">
                    <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
                </normalization>
                <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
                    <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
                    <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
                </punctuation>
                <quotation marks="all">
                    <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
                </quotation>
                <hyphenation eol="all">
                    <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
                </hyphenation>
                <interpretation>
                    <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
                </interpretation>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <creation>
                <date/>
                <rs type="place"/>
            </creation>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <facsimile>
        <graphic xml:id="title" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/goodwife_maxson_harndell_transcription_title.ptif/220,270,1370,1880/400,/!270/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="transcription" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/goodwife_maxson_harndell_transcription.ptif/187,250,1370,1880/400,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="entry1" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/goodwife_maxson_harndell_transcription.ptif/190,840,1340,120/800,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="entry2" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/goodwife_maxson_harndell_transcription.ptif/190,1180,1340,110/800,/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="goodwife1" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/goodwife_maxson_harndell_transcription.ptif/900,850,260,110/full/0/default.jpg"/>
        <graphic xml:id="goodwife2" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/mosher/goodwife_maxson_harndell_transcription.ptif/937,1190,225,90/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    </facsimile>
    <text xml:lang="en-US">
        <head>
            <lb/><hi rend="large">Goodwife Horndall, circa 1646, Newport, Rhode Island</hi>
            <lb/>
            <lb/>by Christopher A. Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, 2021.
        </head>
        <body>
            <div>
                <p>
                    <lb/>The <hi rend="italic">FamilySearch</hi> web site has in its database four index entries
                    that refer to an individual as “<hi rend="bold">Goodwin_</hi>”, the wife of John Horndall. This article
                    shows that these entries are incorrect, and should instead refer to “<hi rend="bold">Goodwife</hi>”.
                </p>
                <head>
                    <lb/><hi rend="large">Database entries</hi>
                </head>
                <p>
                    <lb/>In the <hi rend="italic">FamilySearch</hi> database “Rhode Island Births and Christenings”,
                    there are index entries for the mother in each of two events,
                    <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:V2HH-7PN">birth</ref><hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#bir45">1</ref>]</hi> and
                    <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:4GHR-N92M">baptism</ref><hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#bap45">2</ref>]</hi>,
                    of <hi rend="bold">Mary Horndoll</hi> in 1645. There are two additional index entries for
                    <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:F8Q4-GFQ">birth</ref><hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#bir47">3</ref>]</hi> and
                    <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:F83F-XMC">baptism</ref><hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#bap45">4</ref>]</hi> of
                    another child, also named <hi rend="bold">Mary Horndoll</hi>, in 1647. In each of these four entries,
                    the father is shown as “Jno” and the mother is shown as “<hi rend="bold">Goodwin_</hi>”, that’s
                    with an underscore character at the end of the name. The underscore may indicate that the end of the
                    name is omitted or illegible.
                </p>
                <head>
                    <lb/><hi rend="large">Manuscript pages</hi>
                </head>
                <p>
                    <lb/>All four index entries indicate they were extracted from the same FamilySearch microfilm,
                    <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/search/catalog/69039">“Records of births, marriages, and
                        deaths of the Friends Meeting at Newport, R.I.”</ref>, which is available
                    to the public on-line.<hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#film">5</ref>]</hi> The film contains 143
                    facsimile images of a set of manuscript pages. The pages are approximately 7x9 inches, although the
                    size cannot be determined accurately
                    just by looking at the microfilm. The pages appear to be written on one side only. They all appear to be in
                    the same handwriting, and written at approximately the same time. As indicated on the first page,
                    they are a transcript from some original documents, described as “Friends meeting” records at
                    Newport, Rhode Island. The handwriting is cursive, and very sloppy, with letters being omitted and merged
                    together. There are many abbreviations. The transcription’s pages are sporadically numbered, with
                    some pages having no numbers, and many cases of two subsequent pages having the same number.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <lb/>The transcript may be in the same sequence as the original, because some of the page numbers from
                    the original document are shown. These original page numbers are referred to in the following
                    overview of the arrangement of the entire set of pages:
                    <list>
                        <item>1. Births: surname index, followed by pp. 1-34 of entries</item>
                        <item>2. Marriages: surname index, followed by pp. 1-26 of entries</item>
                        <item>3. Deaths: surname index, followed by pp. 1-20 of entries</item>
                    </list>
                    The entries themselves are in somewhat chronological order, but not consistently so.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <lb/>The <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/3:1:3Q9M-CS3T-6V7X">first
                    page</ref><hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#page1">6</ref>]</hi> of this set of manuscripts
                    has a descriptive title, along with some references this is a copy of some other original item:
                    <lb/><lb/><anchor facs="#title"/>
                    <lb/>Records of Births, Marriages,
                    <lb/>and deaths of the Friends
                    <lb/>meeting at Newport R.I.
                    <lb/>
                    <lb/>Loaned me by J E Woolley the original to
                    <lb/>take home and return next day before
                    <lb/>5 P.M. The book cost him $5 00. to have to
                    <lb/>copy. He never loaned it before -
                    <lb/>I was living in Lex Arr - His grand
                    <lb/>mother was Catrin Cook - He gave the
                    <lb/>book when he died to Shrewsbury Library.
                    <lb/>Quaker
                    <lb/>
                    <lb/>[page is stamped as follows:]
                    <lb/>NEW YORK GENEALOGICAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL SOCIETY
                    <lb/>DEC 7 1934
                </p>
                <p>
                    <head>
                        <lb/><hi rend="large">Horndall births</hi>
                    </head>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <lb/>In first section, “Births”, the manuscript
                    <ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/3:1:3Q9M-CS3T-6VWW">page
                        numbered “12”</ref><hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#page12">7</ref>]</hi>
                    contains the two entries referred to by the <hi rend="italic">FamilySearch</hi> database entries.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <lb/><anchor facs="#transcription"/>
                    <lb/>There are two entries for daughters named “Mary Horndall”:
                    <lb/>
                    <lb/><anchor facs="#entry1"/><hi rend="bold">Mary Horndall d</hi>[aughter of] <hi rend="bold"> Jno &amp; Goodwife 1645</hi>
                    <lb/>
                    <lb/><anchor facs="#entry2"/><hi rend="bold">Mary Horndall d</hi>[aughter of] <hi rend="bold"> Jno &amp; Goodwi 6-5-1647</hi>
                    <lb/>
                    <lb/>This most likely indicates the elder Mary died sometime before the second Mary was born, say circa 1646.
                    There are no other births of “Horndall” (or any similar surname) children shown in the manuscript.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <lb/>One observation is that, although the index entries spell the surname as “Horndoll”, a more accurate reading is “Horndall”.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <lb/>In way of a detailed analysis of these entries, for the first entry after the name of the child,
                    “Mary Horndall”, is a “d” which presumably means “daughter”, since the document does contains entries
                    with masculine names and “s”, for “son”. This is followed by “Jno” which is a traditional abbreviation for “John”.
                    After the ampersand, “&amp;”, is the name of the mother. As seen by examining other entries in this document, this position
                    within the birth entries is reserved for the mother’s <hi rend="italic">given</hi> name. It is never her maiden name, or other surname. In this particular case, the
                    name is given as “<hi rend="bold">Goodwife</hi>”, which (along with the short form Goody) is a traditional
                    Puritan form of address for a respected wife.<hi rend="sup">[<ref target="#goodwife">8</ref>]</hi>
                    The “f” is clearly indicated by its descender extending below the base line, and the ascender extending
                    up to the same height as the ascender of the “d” earlier in the word.
                    The entry for the second “Mary Horndall” is very similar, with what appears to be the same parents,
                    although the mother’s given name is written only as “Goodwi” with the ending of the name being almost
                    illegible. This illegible section may correspond to the underscore in the “Goodwin_” index extracts.
                    <anchor facs="#goodwife1"/><anchor facs="#goodwife2"/>
                    It would be highly unlikely for there to be two different couples,
                    “John Hordall and Goodwife” and “John Hordall and Goodwi” in the local area within two years of each other,
                    so we can safely assume these two entries refer to the same parents. Furthermore, it’s
                    likely the transcriber omitted the ending “fe” from “Goodwife”, rather than the
                    alternative of <hi rend="italic">adding</hi> an “fe” to the end of “Goodwi”. Also, compare the “n” in Horndall to the ending
                    of each of the mother’s names. The characteristic “n” shape, with a horizontal curved segment at the
                    midline level, does not exist at the endings of either of the entries of the mother’s name.
                </p>
                <head>
                    <lb/><hi rend="large">Conclusion</hi>
                </head>
                <p>
                    <lb/>This is not the surname “<hi rend="bold">Goodwin</hi>”, as the index entries claim,
                    based on two key pieces of evidence present in the original manuscript:
                    <list>
                        <item>1. it’s in a position where it would be the <hi rend="italic">given</hi> name of the mother, never the surname
                        standing alone; and,</item>
                        <item>2. the descender of the lower case “f” is prominent, especially in the first entry, and could
                        not possibly be an “n”, which would have no descender.</item>
                    </list>
                    Rather, this is the title “<hi rend="bold">Goodwife</hi>” applied to the wife of John Horndall, with her actual name left unspecified.
                </p>
                <head>
                    <lb/><hi rend="large">References</hi>
                </head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="small">
                        <lb/><ab id="bir45"><hi rend="sup">1</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Rhode Island Births and Christenings, 1600–1914”</title>, database,
                        <title level="m">FamilySearch</title>
                        (<ref target="https://familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:V2HH-7PN"/> : accessed 2021-04-29),
                        <citedRange>entry for Goodwin_ in birth of Mary Horndoll, 1645</citedRange>.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="bap45"><hi rend="sup">2</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Rhode Island Births and Christenings”</title>
                        (<ref target="https://familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:4GHR-N92M"/> : accessed 2021-04-29),
                        <citedRange>database entry for Goodwin_ in baptism of Mary Horndoll, 1645</citedRange>.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="bir47"><hi rend="sup">3</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Rhode Island Births and Christenings”</title>
                        (<ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:F8Q4-GFQ"/> : accessed 2021-04-29),
                        <citedRange>database entry for Goodwin_ in birth of Mary Horndoll, 1647-07-06</citedRange>.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="bap47"><hi rend="sup">4</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Rhode Island Births and Christenings”</title>
                        (<ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/1:1:F83F-XMC"/> : accessed 2021-04-29),
                        <citedRange>database entry for Goodwin_ in baptism of Mary Horndoll, 1647-07-06</citedRange>.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="film"><hi rend="sup">5</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Records of Births, Marriages, and
                        Deaths of the Friends Meeting at Newport, R[hode] I[sland]”</title>
                        (manuscript, 1934, New York Genealogical and Biographical Society);
                        digital images, <title level="m">FamilySearch</title>
                        (<ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/search/catalog/69039"/> : accessed 2021-04-25),
                        FHL microfilm 22488, DGS 7837380.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="page1"><hi rend="sup">6</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Records of Births, Marriages, and Deaths”</title>,
                        <citedRange>title page</citedRange>
                        (<ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/3:1:3Q9M-CS3T-6V7X"/> : accessed 2021-04-25),
                        image 3 of 146.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="page12"><hi rend="sup">7</hi><bibl><title level="u">“Records of Births, Marriages, and Deaths”</title>,
                        <citedRange>births p. 12</citedRange>
                        (<ref target="https://www.familysearch.org/ark:/61903/3:1:3Q9M-CS3T-6VWW"/> : accessed 2021-04-25),
                        image 24 of 146.</bibl></ab>

                        <lb/><ab id="goodwife"><hi rend="sup">8</hi><bibl><title level="m">Wikipedia</title>
                        (<ref target="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Goodwife&amp;oldid=1016346427"/> : accessed 2021-04-25),
                        <title level="u">“Goodwife”</title>, rev. 2021-04-06T17:52:33Z.</bibl></ab>
                    </hi>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
