<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Will of Robert Moger of Gillingham, Dorset, England, 1561</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2021</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2021, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl><title level="u">Will of Robert Moger of Gillingham, Dorset, England, 1561</title>,
        <title level="m">Probate records of the Royal Peculiar of Gillingham, Register of wills</title>;
        P27/1Reg/10B; Wiltshire and Swindon History Centre, Chippenham, Wiltshire, England;
        digital images, <title level="m">Ancestry</title>
        (<ref target="https://www.ancestry.com/imageviewer/collections/61333/images/47286_p27_1reg_10_b_tcl"/> : accessed 2021-05-22).</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="high">
          <p>Diplomatic transcription.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/ftm/mosher_other Media/Wiltshire, England, Wills and Probate, 1530-1858.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text>



<body>

<ab xml:lang="en-emodeng">

<pb facs="#page-001"/>
<lb/><fw type="pageNum" place="top-left">10B</fw>
<lb/>Testamenm̃ Robti Moger ꝑbatm̃ viij die May Anno dom̃ 1561.
<lb/>In the name of god Amen I Robt Moger of the parishe of
<lb/>Gillinghã beyng whole of mynd &amp; memorie thanks be vnto
<lb/>almyghty god &amp; sycke yn my body the xv. of ffebruarie
<lb/>the year of o<hi rend="sup">ꝛ</hi> lord 1559. do make &amp; ordayne my last wyll and
<lb/>testamet̃ after thys man<hi rend="sup">ꝛ</hi> &amp; forme folowyng fyrst I do gyve and
<lb/>bequeath my soule vnto almyghty god to o<hi rend="sup">ꝛ</hi> blessed lady saynt
<lb/>marie the virgyne and to all the blessed company of theabey
<lb/>&amp; my body to be buaryed yn the churche yeard of Gyllingham
<lb/>Itm̃ I do gyve to the mother churche of Briston ij<hi rend="sup">d</hi> And I do
<lb/>gyve vnto the hygh Altare of Gyllinghã vj<hi rend="sup">d</hi> And I gyve to
<lb/>the wode lyght ij<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Itm̃ I gyve &amp; bequeath vnto Margarete Marshe
<lb/>my daughter one cowe And vnto Edith Moger my sons daughter
<lb/>a reade heafer &amp; a crocke <surplus reason="repeated">&amp; a crocke</surplus> &amp; a pan Also I do gyve &amp;
<lb/>bequeath vnto Iohn Moger &amp; vnto Robert Moger my sonnes
<lb/>chyldren to eche of them one steare bullocke of one yere aige
<lb/>And I do gyve vnto Osmund Moger my sonnes son a mare colte
<lb/>Also I do gyve vnto Edith Moger the yonger of my sonnes daughters
<lb/>one brynded heafer of one yeres aige And I do gyve vnto Katheryn
<lb/>Moger my sonnes Daughter the beste cowes calf to be waned and
<lb/>kept to her ꝑfyt &amp; vse. And to Iohn Moger my sonnes son a calf
<lb/>to be waned ij. yeres hereafter for the chylds ꝑfyt &amp; vse. And I
<lb/>gyve vnto Iohn Newman my daughters son one calf to be waned
<lb/>for hym a thre yeres hereafter for hys ꝑfyt &amp; vse. And to every god
<lb/>chyld ij<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. The resydew of my goods my Debtes payed I gyve and
<lb/>bequeath vnto my son Richard Moger whom I do make &amp; ordayne to
<lb/>be my heole &amp; sole execut<hi rend="sup">ꝛ</hi> And I make my overseers Edward
<lb/>Shepeherd &amp; Nicholas Brewer <del rend="overstrike">wytne</del> wytnisses to thys
<lb/>wyll Thomas Kyng prieste Matthew Nayler w&#x036d; other

</ab>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
