<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Will of John Moger, of London, England, 1591</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2021</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2021, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl><title level="u">Will of John Moger, of London, England, 1591</title>,
        <title level="m">Prerogative Court of Canterbury, Will Registers, Sainberbe</title>;
        PROB11/77, folio 401 (recto, verso);
        digital images, <title level="m">Ancestry</title>
        (<ref target="https://www.ancestry.com/imageviewer/collections/5111/images/40611_311345-00810"/> : accessed 2021-06-03).</bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="high">
          <p>Diplomatic transcription.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/ftm/mosher_other Media/England &amp; Wales, Prerogative Court of Canterbury Wills, 1384-1858(9).jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-002" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/ftm/mosher_other Media/40611_311345-00811.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text>



<body>

<ab xml:lang="en-emodeng">
<pb n="folio 401 recto" facs="#page-001"/>
<lb/><hi rend="large">In the name of god: amen</hi> the xxviij<hi rend="sup">th</hi>
<lb/>daye of Maye a thousand ffyue hundred nynetie one Elizabeth &amp; Regine : xxxiij I Iohn
<lb/>Moger Citizen and Cooke of London being whole of Bodie and of perfect minde and ~ ~
<lb/>Remembraunce praise be giuen to Almightie god but yet doubtefull of the Lordes ~ ~
<lb/>visitacõn and allso my Suddeyne callinge by deathe do constitute and ordeyne ~
<lb/>this my last will and testament in manner and forme followinge. ffirst I ~ ~
<lb/>bequeathe my soule vnto the handes of Almightie god my heauenlye father ~
<lb/>and to Iesus xp̅iste his onlie sonne my Redemer with thassisance of the holie ghost
<lb/>my daylie Sanctifier in whome and by whome I hope to be in the nomber of the ~
<lb/>Elete at the generall Resurrection vntill which tyme I committ my Bodie to the earth
<lb/>Item I will and bequeathe vnto my Brother william Moger Citizen and Cooke of
<lb/>London all my lande in Bromley in the Countie of Kente that hath ben in varyaunce
<lb/>betwene hym and me and to his heires for euer. Item I giue and bequeathe vnto my ~
<lb/>Cosin Oliver Moger the younger sonne of Oliver Moger deceased all y Landes in
<lb/>Nockoll in the countie of Kente which was my ffather in lawe John Myborn ^ yeoman ? deceased
<lb/>to hym and to his heires males of his Bodie lawfullie begotten. And for want
<lb/>of suche yssue of heires males of his bodie lawfullie begotten I do giue my saied landes
<lb/>in Nockell vnto ffedricke his brother and to the heires males of his Bodie law=
<lb/>fullie begotten. And for defaulte of suche yssue then I giue and bequeathe my saied
<lb/>Landes in Nockell vnto Robert Moger his brother: and to the heires males of his
<lb/>Bodie lawfullie begotten. And for wante of suche heires males of theire Bodies ~
<lb/>lawfullie begotten then I will and bequeathe my saied Landes in Nockell to my ~
<lb/>Brother william and his heires for euer. Item I giue and bequeathe to Oliver ~
<lb/>Moger the younger the somme of twentie pounde to be paied vnto hym when he
<lb/>shall accomplishe or come to his full age of one and twentie yeres. Item I do giue
<lb/>and bequeathe vnto ffredricke Moger his Brother the somme of twentie poundes ~
<lb/>when he shall come to his full age of one and twentie yeres. Item I giue and bequeathe
<lb/>vnto Robert Moger his Brother the somme of twentie poundes to be paied vnto hym
<lb/>when he shall accomplishe his full age of one and twentie yeres. Item I do giue and
<lb/>bequeathe vnto Margaret Moger theire Sister the somme of twentie poundes when
<lb/>she shall come to her full age of twentie yeres or at the daye of her marriage. Item
<lb/>I do giue and bequeathe vnto her Sister ffrauncis Moger the somme of twentie
<lb/>poundes when she shall come to her full age of twentie yeres or at the daye of her
<lb/>marriage. Item I do giue and bequeathe vnto Iohn Halpenye sonne of Iohn ~
<lb/>Halpenye of Orpington in the countie of Kent the Somme of twentie poundes
<lb/>when he shall come to his full age of one and twentie yeres. Item I giue and ~
<lb/>bequeathe vnto Henry Halpenye his Brother the somme of twentie poundes to be
<lb/>paied vnto hym when he shall come to his full age of one and twentie yeres. Itm
<lb/>I do giue and bequeathe vnto Andrewe Halpenye the somme of twentie poundes
<lb/>to be paied vnto hym when he shall come to his full age of one and twentie yeres
<lb/>Item I do giue and bequeathe vnto Agnes halpenye theire sister the somme of
<lb/>twentie poundes to be paied vnto her when she shall come to her full age of twenty
<lb/>yeres of at the daye of her marriage. Allse my will and intente ys that none
<lb/>of them shall sell any of their porcoñs of money or Legacey be me giuen before ~
<lb/>they shall come to theire full ages yf he she or any of them shall so happen to doe
<lb/>Then my will and intente is that he she or they which so dothe shall have no porc̃on
<lb/>of money or legacey by me giuen to them. And allso my will is that yf any of
<lb/>them happen to die them my will is that he or she whoe dyeth then his of her ~
<lb/>porc̃on so dyinge shall remayne and to be Deuided amongest the rest porc̃on and
<lb/>porc̃on like. Item I do giue vnto twentie of my ffellowes men and women of þ<hi rend="sup">e</hi>
<pb n="folio 401 verso" facs="#page-002"/>
<lb/>poorer sorte tenne poundes to be deuided amongest them and to be paied vnto them within
<lb/>twentie dayes after my decease. Item I do will and allso bequeathe vnto them within
<lb/>that my executors and ouerseers hereunder named shall see that all theise my Legaceys
<lb/>and porc̃ons of money giuen to the children shall after my decease be put forthe to
<lb/>be ymployed for theire most advauntage and allso taking good suerties and Bandes
<lb/>for the payment thereof accordinge to my true meaninge and truste in them. All
<lb/>the rest of my goodes vnbequeated my Legacys paied my ffunerall dischard god
<lb/>and my Bodie broughte honestlie to the grounde the one halfe I do giue to be given
<lb/>and deuided amongest the poore of the parishe of Brumley in the countie of Kent
<lb/>And the other halfe to be devided amongest my Bretheren and Sisters children ~
<lb/>aforesaied portion and portion like. All whiche goodes vnbequeathed to be sould
<lb/>and so deuided and giuen aswell to the poore as to my Bretheren and Sisters ~ ~
<lb/>children: and to be deuided and given by my executors and ouerseers. And of ~
<lb/>this my last will and testament I do ordeyne and make Iohn Sonckey gentleman one of
<lb/>my executors: And I do giue vnto hym for his paynes the somme of tenne poundes. And
<lb/>I do make another of my executors Iames Blandcharde citizen and draper of Londõ
<lb/>and I do giue vnto hym for his paynes ffyue poundes. Allso I do make my ouerseers ~
<lb/>william Moger Citizen and Cooke of London and Iohn kinlye of Grenewiche in the
<lb/>countie of Kent yeoman and do giue vnto them the Somme of ffyue poundes. Item
<lb/>I do by this my will and last testamente forgiue all and all manner of persons that
<lb/>oweth vnto me any somme or sommes of money be yt by bill or obligac̅on that is vnd<hi rend="sup">ꝛ</hi>
<lb/>three pounde sixe shillinges eighte pence. Item I do giue vnto my ffellowe Iohn ~
<lb/>Osmonde all my chests and upparell in my chaumber in the Rolles. In witnesse
<lb/>hereof to this my last will and testamente I haue put to my hande and seale the
<lb/>daie and yere abouewritten and in the presentes of vs hereundernamed Sealed signed
<lb/>and deliuered in the presence of vs Geoffrey yate Ro? kighleye / ~ / ~ / Iohn Moger
</ab>
<p>
<lb/><hi rend="large">Probatum fuit testamentũ</hi>
<lb/>Suprascripum apud London coram venerabili viro Magistro Willmo ?ewin legu?
<lb/>doctore ad excertend? off? Mayistri Custodis suie Comissarij Cuen? ?
<lb/>Cantuariem? ? Deputat Septimo die mensie Iunij Anno Domini millesimo
<lb/>quingentesimo nonage simo primo Iuramento Iohannis Sonckey et Iacobi Blanch<hi rend="sup">rd</hi>
<lb/>Executorum in hmoi? testamento nominat Com? comissa fuit Administraco bonorum
<lb/>Iurium et cueditorum dci defuncti de bene et fideliter Administrand ad sancto dei
<lb/>Evangelia Iurat / ~ / ~ / ~ / ex<hi rend="sup">ꝛ</hi>
</p>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
