<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>harrison deed 1831</title>
        <author/>
        <principal>Christopher Alan Mosher</principal>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>Christopher Alan Mosher</authority>
        <pubPlace>Shelton, CT, USA</pubPlace>
        <date>2018</date>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <p>Copyright © 2018, Christopher Alan Mosher, Shelton, Connecticut, USA.</p>
          <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <editorialDecl>
        <correction status="low">
          <p>OCR generated transcript has not been corrected.</p>
        </correction>
        <normalization method="markup">
          <p>Only minor normalization where needed, if any, is indicated via markup.</p>
        </normalization>
        <punctuation marks="all" placement="internal">
          <p>All punctuation marks in the source text have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
          <p>Punctuation may be marked up with pc elements for clarification, but not exclusively.</p>
        </punctuation>
        <quotation marks="all">
          <p>All quotation marks have been retained, and are represented by appropriate Unicode code points.</p>
        </quotation>
        <hyphenation eol="all">
          <p>Hyphenated words that appear at the end of a line have been retained. The hyphen, if present, is represented by the Unicode code point, and marked up with a pc element. The break="no" attribute on the lb element indicates that a single word is split across the lines.</p>
        </hyphenation>
        <interpretation>
          <p>Dates, places, and names may be marked up, where useful.</p>
        </interpretation>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <creation>
        <date/>
        <rs type="place"/>
      </creation>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en-US">English (USA)</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <graphic xml:id="page-000" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/harrison/harrison_deed_1831/p-000.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-001" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/harrison/harrison_deed_1831/p-001.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-002" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/harrison/harrison_deed_1831/p-002.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
    <graphic xml:id="page-003" url="https://mosher.mine.nu/images/genealogy/main/sources/old/harrison/harrison_deed_1831/p-003.ptif/full/full/0/default.jpg"/>
  </facsimile>
  <text xml:lang="en-US">
    <body>
      <ab rend="grid"><pb n="1" facs="#page-000"/><lb/>-'r
<lb/>r
<pb n="2" facs="#page-001"/><lb/>b-v"'tir--
<lb/>pprfvj
<lb/>lyryj lO-^^ IPV^
<lb/>^ 72?
<pb n="3" facs="#page-002"/><lb/>u
<lb/>•WATlkTLMMT"^
<lb/>This Indenture, m.ae
<lb/>the Year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred andrj ^ 5
<lb/>„  y. M''
<lb/>of the fi rst part, and U&lt;^cn:a-- , ^ , V . ,WITNESSETH, That the said partu^&gt; of the first part, to
<lb/>Dollars lawful money of the United States, to ptoyr^ mhais hereby confessed and acknowledged; Bai^e. granted, bar
<lb/>these presents Do grant, bargain, sell, remi^, ah^, arid
<lb/>and assigns forever, ALL cAyttli^ nL^
<lb/>TOGETHER with all and singular the hereditaments and t
<lb/>the reversion and reversions, remainder and remainders, re
<lb/>claim and demand whatsoever, of the said parti^^ oi the tii
<lb/>premises, with the said hereditaments and appurtenances :
<lb/>hereby granted premises, with the said hereditaments and e
<lb/>said part^ of the second part, heirs and assigns, t
<lb/>of the se^nd part, heirs and assigns, forever. A
<lb/>heirs, executors and administrators, do covenant, grar
<lb/>ond part, heirs and assigns, that immedia^k befori
<lb/>ises of an estate in fee simple therein and also to
<lb/>■ every part and parcel tliet eof against the said ^h«
<lb/>against all and every other person or persons claiming or t
<lb/>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the said part of the prst
<lb/>written.
<lb/>■££ALED ANO DBIilVEHED IN PSESENCE
<pb n="4" facs="#page-003"/>
<lb/>Vrmtc^bv B. F, SME^T» BATH.
<lb/>the
<lb/>BETWEEN .^.
<lb/>1 ^;r OLit-CX,
<lb/>I
<lb/>j  X " - of the second part
<lb/>r and in consideration of the sum of G^hx- }iAx4-i l/i^Cl ^
<lb/>]d paid, by the said part^ of the second part, the receipt whereof
<lb/>gained, sold, remised, released, aliened, and confirmedj^ and by
<lb/>confirm, unto the said part^ of the second part, and to , heirs
<lb/>^ /&gt;-, krtf^ , nx c£'i jM^ ni^ tIZ.QmIXjlj P/^. CO-L, •^U^OU yxtZZOiXju (X^
<lb/>partenances theveur-to belonging, or In any wise appertaining, and
<lb/>s, issues and profits tliereof; and all the estate, right, title, interest,
<lb/>, part, or either in law or equity, of. in and to the above bargained
<lb/>ho HAVE AND TO HOLD all and singular the above described and
<lb/>ourtenances thereunto belonging or in any wise appertaining to ye
<lb/>:he sole and only proper use, benefit and behoof of the y^jpart
<lb/>D the said hCGHZ p r- band f&lt;n .teirbargain, p'romise and agree, to and with the said part^ of the sec-
<lb/>he ensealing and delivery hereof yiNitr:- seized of the said prem-
<lb/>If I; and forever to the above bargained premises, and
<lb/>,rst part, heirs, executors, administrators and assigns, anclaim the said premises, or any part thereof. *
<lb/>art ha hereunto set hand and seal the day and yeat firs a o ^
<lb/>'&gt;-1
<lb/>'il
<lb/>i
</ab>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
